<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>RustyNotes - Chaos</title>
    <subtitle>A journey with some Rust</subtitle>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com/tags/chaos/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2022-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://rustynotes.com/tags/chaos/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-1 Control and Chaos</title>
        <published>2022-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-1-control-and-chaos/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-1-control-and-chaos/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-1-control-and-chaos&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-1 Control and Chaos&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching a person in youtube. His name is Ray Holiday and the channel is daily stoic. In one of the videos he mentioned about writing andhow many books he has written by just being consistent. It seems like enough to create a basein our life. He suggests that to write journal every day. For this goal he has published a book with questions to answer and guide us every day. Then i decided to buy this book but during search i have discovered he is the writer of The daily stoic:366 meditations on wisdom, perseverence and the art of living. I decided buying this book first. This post is my first writingfor the first topic in the book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says the wisdom starts with understanding what we can control and what we cannot. If we stop worrying about the things we cannot control and put our effort and energy to the things wecan control we fullfill a lot. Other way around seems like waste. As saying says:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God grant me the serenity to accept the things i cannot change, the courage to change the things i can and the wisdom to know the difference.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection of the things we will think and put effort is first step. This is core for a more resilient life and character. We cannot take distance with much distraction which is mostly by purpose. Pick the things you can control and change. Do not overthink and distur yourself with the stuff you cannot change, you cannot control. Welcome to the core of stoic lifestyle. Suffering is okay, but for the right thing. For the thing will carry you to the next point. Don&#x27;t spent much time in past and also future. Today is same day. It is one of days which brings us here. Not past not future, today will give the life, today will shape the life. Don&#x27;t focus others, keep your focus on today. On the thing may change the results.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
