<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>RustyNotes - Writing</title>
    <subtitle>A journey with some Rust</subtitle>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com/tags/writing/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://rustynotes.com/tags/writing/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The resistance</title>
        <published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-resistance&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The resistance&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no rule and order in context and title. They are just a piece of my daily feelings, experience, and learning progress.
Today I have just decided to write about resistance. Because yesterday I couldn&#x27;t start to write.
I wanted but there was no idea and motivation. Creating a habit is always hard because we are not able to see the future and end of our path.
We may feel satisfied but also we can regret it after spending some years. When we force ourselves to do what we don&#x27;t want we treat ourselves like a maid.
At this point there should be a border, we shouldn&#x27;t tyrannize ourselves and should find a way and create a tactic to keep us on our way but also
train us by having tough times. We need to evoke ourselves in a way and see what we are doing. Otherwise, it might be too late for decisions and change.
There is no exact truth but searching and having a meaning and goal will be helpful for the future.
To develop our credibility we should look to people who have a better life and read about their lives so we can decide more wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exact&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;satisfied&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;credibility&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;channel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cassette&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;habit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tactic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evoke&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The goal and way of writing</title>
        <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-goal-and-way-of-writing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The Goal and way of writing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method is very old. We all get lessons about it but we don&#x27;t pay enough attention because writing is a boring activity for children. So we grow up without improving this skill enough. After some years of experience in business and also communication paths in daily life we understand how important is the usage of language and richness in vocabulary. Now we all know that communication skills and consistency are the most important skills in life. So, we need to improve ourselves in these skills. According to Jordan Peterson, we need to write more and more to use the language more effectively and order our ideas to think more clearly and properly. By that time I have been thinking about consistency and effective ways of getting this skill. By getting an impression from the homework the teacher gave us and suggesting to do more, I decided to write consistently, almost every day. These two activities will be a perfect fit for lots of problems especially are related to personal identification, communication, and expression. The way of doing this is by defining 10 random words and using 6 of them in a context. Cooperation by others will make it more interesting, interactive, and also more effective. Because seeing others&#x27; writings about the same words will improve our creativity and our own writing. The rhythm we have and keep for that habit will define our progress. When we execute this plan well we will get lifelong durable and very important skills. Otherwise, we will be in the case of resigning ourselves to the lives we don&#x27;t like because of weak character and personality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identification&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resign&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cooperation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amputate&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diamond&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rhythm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;execute&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rugby&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Golden halfmoon</title>
        <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-town&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Town&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town we will talk about is Halfeti. It is part of the city named Sanliurfa which is famous for being the source of religion in the world. In my country, we call this city the city of prophets. Because lots of prophets have been there during history, like Muse, Abraham, Elyasa, Adem, Ayub. And also a temple named Göbeklitepe dates back to 9500 BC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During endless stream of time, the city managed to survive in mandatory of different countries. In this matter, the town Halfeti has a unique position in one respect. It has a castle in the middle of the river which were defining the border of the Eastern Roman Empire. When you see the picture of the castle you see how fairly reasonable to build it there. It is like the wall in the game of thrones. Because the river still defines the east in Turkey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pass the west side you should pass across the river. Besides, according to the book Homo Sapiens, the River Euphrates defines the Fertile Crescent with another river named Tigris. The region around these two rivers was very productive and important during history so the agriculture, religion, and writing were sourced from Fertile Crescent. Nowadays, the situation is slightly different. Rivers are still very important but industries were not established there. Despite being so historic they don&#x27;t have enough amenities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Halfeti people has a living just from agriculture. The discovery of the first temple of the world in Urfa started to attract tourists. Moreover, having a sub-merged town under the river makes the Halfeti attractive for tourists. Some parts are photogenic but it was a ghost town when I was a child. Nowadays, it is a lively town with sailing, canoe, and diving amenities. There are not many residents and no imposing buildings. Also, because of the narrow streets, I suggest that to leave your car on the main road and walk. Because it is a Cita Slow with a gentle rhythm and a self-contained environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The middle man</title>
        <published>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-middle-men-and-old-man&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Middle men and old man&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle. Middle of what? Who knows? He always felt like this without any idea for reason. He was brought up in a conservative family that potentially was in the heart of his life. But he doesn&#x27;t want to remember those days anymore. He knows how he felt after expelling from school and being like on the ledge of family. His father was like a sheer wall for every discussion and preventing him to shape his own way. Maybe that was because of buzzing news about war and the bad economy, but there should have been more. He has never known that. Because, after staying in the zone and hard working he got the foot in the door of university and left them behind. He hasn&#x27;t looked back after this moment and flashed around the country with his exam scores. Everyone was stunned because it was impossible to work flawlessly in that conditions. It was merely a small possibility to rally after this long period of indolence life. But they had forgotten how greasy he is for his decisions and after deciding to his way how hard to change his mind. Now he was at the summit of Mont Blanc and has just signed the summit book. He was standing on his planted steps with an old feeling like being in the middle of a low surrounding.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle of foreigners. They had come from far but he was from the city. Unlike others, he felt fatigued in the middle of the way but he rallied by staying in the zone and pushing towards his limits. In the end, these bad feelings turned into being stunned due to the accomplishment of this goal. Because it was a merely impossible dream for someone at that age. After he explained his decision, all family members warned him about how this event potentially can kill him. They said that he was in the heart of the family and he shouldn&#x27;t do that. However, it was not true and he has felt like he is on the ledge of the family until this moment. Now he was standing over planted steps in the summit. This was the point he got his foot in the door of climbing and became the oldest person who climbed to Mont Blanc. The news was buzzing this journey and it flashed around the world.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man was fainted due to lack of sleep and fatigue. Because he had already been sick. Writing and staying in the zone for several hours was potentially dangerous. The doctor and all family members warned him but after getting his foot in the door of writing he became more undeterred and it was impossible to dissuade him. He was a famous writer and had flashed around the world once upon a time. So, even getting stuck in some points he rallied to finish this book before the party. The book was supposed to be a birthday gift the next day. There was merely a small time before the party and the book was finally completed. Everything was working flawlessly according to his plan. The girl would be stunned when she saw the book had written for her. The old man closed the book and named it by using one of the greasy tags. He wasn&#x27;t aware of the broken door ledge and also that the name will have been buzzing in the news the next day. Because it was the last book of a great writer who was at the summit of his career. During his long and successful journey, he hasn&#x27;t looked back but it was time to rest last time. By this book, an old saying is brought up again. There is no reward without taking risks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;by listening rock&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
