<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>RustyNotes - English</title>
    <subtitle>A journey with some Rust</subtitle>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com/tags/english/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://rustynotes.com/tags/english/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Freedom and lose</title>
        <published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/freedom-and-lose/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/freedom-and-lose/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-freedom-and-lose&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Freedom and lose&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was winter lost time. I was spending all day in library and doing interviews in several places all around city. When I think about these days it feel to far, too strange and too powerful. How come I kept fighting? What was the motivation? How come I survived in too strange situations? Calling them strange for not hurting anyone. But I know how they were. I probably will forget like I did for all bad memories. Actually I don&#x27;t forget, but brain blocks the feelings from that time to come surface. Remembering too quick and jumping to another place to stay away from risk and damage. I will never be able write about them. Nobody will never know. Maybe I will find a foreigner and tell the story and let him go. I can&#x27;t live with it. Everyday I am thinking about that days. Still don&#x27;t understand how was it. How I managed! How! What was the thing kept me alive!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like I was lucky. Could end up losing all life and projections. I have to write about it but not here. I have to burn it after writing. Can&#x27;t dare to face it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to write about something totally different. The fight of freedom and losing it. The feeling I have for the society, folks. There is no freedom for us anymore. Fight ended. We all lost the hope for a freedom. Life of nations are too long with thousands of struggles. Some nations will never reach peace. They already lost several times. In terrible conditions, will never have ability to win against power. Power brings more power, wins brings more win. And all was accumulated. Rest in sorrow and your small peace my people. Life is too big.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A man far away</title>
        <published>2025-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/a-man-far-away/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/a-man-far-away/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-a-man-far-away&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) A man far away&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a video hitting hard. He talks about a man who chooses to walk alone and stays untouched. When you meet a man with few friends or not at all, don&#x27;t mistake it as a weakness. One genuine friend holds more value than hundreds of phony. His trust is earned. His value is time, treating it like royalty. His power comes from within. That someone you don&#x27;t wanna come across. He has seen fake friendships, drama and betrayal in others. He is completely his own. He does not need your approval. While others chase validation he has cut it all out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Feeling alive</title>
        <published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/feeling-alive/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/feeling-alive/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-feeling-alive&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Feeling alive&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My vocabulary is not rich to explain this feeling, i don&#x27;t know how to explain it. I even don&#x27;t know is there anyone feeling same, is there a word to explain my feeling. I don&#x27;t think there is someone feels like me. Here and now. I feel alive, with someone inside me smiling, excited for living. It is not me i think. It is something growing in me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This things happens just i help a friend, i have a good time with a friend. When i cought fired and wanna run to everywhere, wanna use all seconds i have. To get more of it, to go the place they want to see me. The life i supposed to live. Fire will turn normal after some time. But memory will help me to set day. I live for the day i will meet my friends. I have nothing bigger. When i meet they should get smile, joy, power, courage, all we need.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When i was a teenager. I was carrying hundreds of books in each travel to home. Now, my home is my friends. I will carry something they need, something they like for my whole life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no goal bigger than others happiness. People has no personal happiness. It is all about folk around us. We don&#x27;t get happy. We make happiness. Yes, you cannot be happy. You make happy. Let me leave a poem from Emily Dickinson.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I&#x27;m nobody! Who are you?
&lt;p&gt;Are you nobody, too?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&#x27;s a pair of us - don&#x27;t tell!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&#x27;d banish us, you know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How dreary to be somebody!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How public, like a frog&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tell your name the &amp;gt; livelong day&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To an admiring bog!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Which person</title>
        <published>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-80-which-person/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-80-which-person/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-which-person-are-you-becoming&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Which person are you becoming?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shame on me! Last time i have posted something was 8-15. More than 40 days with nothing. What kind of failure i am in? Is this the person i want to be? Is this the person i am? Is this the one i will become? I have written some parts on napkins to be secure. I have written some hard stuff and thrown them. I can not post my all feelings and situations. They are bad, not just to me, from me, but also to life. I don&#x27;t want being in this kins of situations again. I will save myself, i have no solution yet but i may find a away to get rid of shit people and find my qualified fiends again.
Today&#x27;s topic was habits and the person we want to become. It is so clear. And it is the thing makes me write. I have to be a person understand his feelings and others, understands life concepts and apply good principles on journey.
As i see i have to develop habits beside social skills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of all, i have to write. Everyday. It helps a lot to understand whole. Almost anything will be easier when we write it down. I have to develop a writing habit. I already have one but it is not stable. Like my character. Surviving in waves. And losing shore and path regularly.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondly, i have to progress in m proffession. I have to read and code everyday. I do that, i like it more than anything.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, i have to develop my body with gym, running, tennis and swimming. I don&#x27;t need more sports then these. Gym is going fine, i visit almost three times in a week. Tennis is once in a week for now. But there is no swimming. I need to register to pool later. Running is not here yet, i lost it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And my weakest point, social life. I have to put some effort to build a life. Which i have never reeached to a level i want. I need to read books loud. I will join dancing clubs. I will join running clubs. I will join volunteering organizations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday i was listening someone(Mahmut) from red pill. Who has great knowledge and deep understanding of life. He said if you want to control everything you have to be alone. Otherwise in relationship with people you will lose some freedom and control. The poeple you add your life will add a factor of uncertainty. He just hit it. I experinced that and run away from it to get whole control of life. In the beginning of university i was among poeple who has connection with everybody. Then i felt i like i give a lot and there is nothing remaining for me. I disparted myself to get more control and more freedom. I Reached a point i am totally free. I am still there, freedom and control is so nice and hard to give up. But like termodynamics and physics there is a tradeoff freedom and control. I have to get a balance in my life. I have to trade my freedom and control with some joy and connection. This is an important part of life i sacrified totally for a long time. And as a famous quote(feel like from Shophenhauer) says life is like pendellum. When you lack you feel bad for not having, when you reach it you get bored of it. And know the most i lack is the social one, the most i am looking for is this one. The feeling is because of lackness, maybe because of importance but i don&#x27;t think. Whatever you lack, it gets the most important one you think, you suffer, it stress you out.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Being me(n)</title>
        <published>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/being-me-n/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/being-me-n/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-being-me-n&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Being me(n)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last post was 12 days ago. How? What was i doing that time?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t remember. I did some study by skipping writing but it was just a few days. It seems like i lost the connection with this habit. I don&#x27;t do it for fun and with fun. I have to do it. I can not heal myself otherwise. There is no one can hep me, can solve me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today i watched a video in youtube in my desperate situation. It was nice to recover and set mind again. I am here - back by this video. Title is &amp;quot;Being Men&amp;quot;. But i changed as &amp;quot;Being Me(n)&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there was a saying in video. It says being avarage sucks. It really sucks when you tasted success at one point in your life. This is me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you need to love pain. Mentally and physcologically. This is me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you come here you have to put effort on it. Go hard. Or turn back to your country - your home. This is me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So i need to be me to be a men.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Inspired</title>
        <published>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-79-inspired/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-79-inspired/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-inspired&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Inspired&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World is full of people inspired. Most are inspired by some historic people or living one. What that means? Showing a clue for person, for character. Nothing more. The thing we need action, becoming inspiring. Not staying inspired.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We cannot stand with wrong, even if it is our internal wrong. We have to do the right thing. We can&#x27;t just sit and wait. We can&#x27;t lie and stay in peace. I am not sure how these poeple managing this conflict with thei ideal life, ideal partner, ideal person.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the way to have an iamge in mind for future and behave in reverse is super hard for most people. Most are misserable in this, they just can&#x27;t change and become ideal step by step. But there is another type. They stay away from virtues. They know they are lier, they know they just use others for their pleasure. They manage to do it again and again without hesitation. I don&#x27;t know whether should we have regret or not? Is being lier and doing everything for goals fine? What kind of failure they will have. They hit the goals and never feel hesitation for the way. In short term and long term, they win. Why should we follow the virtues, follow the doctrin. It says society values being right and honest. But i don&#x27;t think. If you don&#x27;t shine with your lies and if don&#x27;t cover your failure, weakness, the one with lies will come and pick up the prize. You will staying on side. As regular, basic person, you have no point in this race. So what? Why should we stay honest, humble, naive, friendly? Who likes this! People are looking for a fighter, they want adventure, not sitting in peace. And old doctrin is not workign anymore. There is no aggrement over honesty and loyalty. There is interest on joy and power.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Right Choice</title>
        <published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-77-right-choice/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-77-right-choice/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-right-choice&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Right Choice&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is good and bad? Is this important? Is there any evil, any good outside? Whether something rewarded, whether something will succeed. But whether it is the right choice!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good and bad. Is it real? Are they here, are they something we can know? Or are they just quick dense answers to cover all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real thing is right choice. Not where it goes. Having a rational mind and focus only the choices. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Yesterday</title>
        <published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-78-yesterday/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-78-yesterday/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-yesterday&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Yesterday&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is gone forever. Sliped from my fingers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was there, i was going to seize it. I was going to live the day. With its 24 hours. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew it, i knew that i am going to lose it. It was passing. Didn&#x27;t stop and left me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost it, forever. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Beauty</title>
        <published>2024-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-76-beauty/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-76-beauty/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-beauty&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Beauty&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic lottery. This is what we count as beauty. It is beauty. I can not say it is not. I will not create counter arguments. They may say internal values, character, duty and dicipline is part of person and they are us all together. Yes this is also right. Beauty is not just one, people may have several beauty. If they are together it is great. It would be a wonderful composision for any person. We all want all together. When i write we i feel like i share the sin, i share guilt. I always prefer to use we for uncomfortable things. Just to share the mess and carry less. Now lets say, I want all, I have always wanted more. I may know it is immossible and i will die before reaching goal. But i want all beauty together. I want more and more. Sounds ridicilous, but i know it. I am like you, if you have two options you always ask a better one. All together. Yes i want all beauty and and i am not willing to accept something with less beauty. Maybe i will accept my mistake and go with regular. Maybe worse than regular. Maybe i just need to go. Whatever it is, i have to go. I don&#x27;t know. Am i lucky enough, do i have that courage to obtain something. I don&#x27;t think. Not yet. I am still weak, still far from my goals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to be good by doing things good for me and future. Maybe i will reach somewhere but not sure. I need more actions and development in social skills to get a life i want. A good day means it is with good things. I can count this days as good. But you know we always want more. It has to be better. It is not that good. It is not like i imagined. Maybe it will never be. Maybe there is no good days out of dreams. They are just dreams.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Jose mujica</title>
        <published>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-75-jose-mujica-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-75-jose-mujica-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-jose-mujica&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Jose Mujica&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page was about money and spending. We all know some super rich people and how much they spend for their basics and luxuries. It is so simple to spend when we give someone lots of money. Having parties, buying lots of stuff. But what about Jose and Seneca. Seneca sold furniture in palace to pay dept, Jose donated 90 percent of his money with his car to charity. I met him once in Istanbul, and i will never forget him. He is a real person with great pain and still good. Spend years in prison, spend almost all he has for country. He knows that is real in this life. Real thing is how you feel. Not spending and buying. You can not buy yourself. You need to create.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next page says you are the material for your work. Life all professions, worker has metarial to work on and create great products. Professionals spend lots of time and effort for training and getting master of their field. Like tennis players, metarial is body and game. They practice to get perfect in it. Or like engineers they need to learn system design and development with all details and innovation methods. What about us? What about our life and its raw metarial: our mind. We have develop an approach to master our mind. We have to spend most time and effort on it. On profession of life. To be good in our life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Act is core</title>
        <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-74-act-is-core/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-74-act-is-core/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-act-is-core&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Act is core&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is nice. It is about one of the most important things, action. I totally aggree. Action is core for all we have, all we get, all we are. We have to act for whatever issue is. Our action is the way, it is path. Nothing more will give us goals, destinations, results. Without action, any kind of effort is mostly waste. Waste of a life has taken an action. Like my great t-short says &#x27;Take Action&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next page is about actions again. But actions shaped by knowledge, generated by processing ideas, actions shows your character, your wisdom, your discipline. Like our shoulders showing our gym habits and effort, our actions should show our knowledge, our expertise, our approach to life. Give yourself time to digest theories you get and put effort to get outcome. Use it to shape yourself, to shape your actions, your life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Character</title>
        <published>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-73-character/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-73-character/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-character&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Character&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, i didn&#x27;t want to write, i was angry again, miserable again. I don&#x27;t want to write it down here but you know we can&#x27;t pick our family and we can&#x27;t throw it away. I think i have to do it but i am still stupid. I am still not powerful to reject that mass and damage. What kind of idiot am i? I tried to stay away and leave alone then i did. But they still can reach me. They still can mass up with my life, my mind, my progress. They steal all i have. All energy, all time, all money, all hope, all life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to cut all connection with this problem. I did it now in my mind. It is clear. I will never let it destroy my mood and flow. I will save myself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lost control and grabed it now. And will never let it slip away. It is mine and now i want to write from book i read. The page i read has a great title: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make character your loudest statement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is super clear. And i am lucky that i know the feeling. I know having a character speaking for you. Having people know you by your character. It speaks them, it speaks in everywhere, before you speak, without your speaking, without your existance. It always speaks. It has no border, no time. And it is loudest. There is nothing can speak better than your character. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Inside out</title>
        <published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-71-inside-out/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-71-inside-out/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-inside-out&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Inside out&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In and out are two of our perspectives. Having different perspectives helps us to see things in more clear view. Like walking aroung an object to understand what it is. How easy to judge and count things as wrong and as mistake. In which time? Things have different aspects and they usually change by time. Now you see, you see that we have nothing. How correct can be our ideas? With our single vision stamped by now. And have lots of different views in different people and times. What kind of mistake is really mistake? I mean not our mistakes, the things we count as mistake by others. Even our mistakes are not that clear. There is in and out, short term and long term. And feelings in us and others. It is not binary, we can not decide for most. We fail in most. And why, why we decide? Why don&#x27;t we keep it as it is, letting it comes as it is as whole. With more views, we may see something truely. Maybe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Desire</title>
        <published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-72-desire/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-72-desire/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-desire&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Desire&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desire is the key. Desire is the way. For what?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know you desire. You want. You expect. Then, you shape for it. You serve toward the goal, toward aim of desire. You need to get it. You do what you need for it. You change. You chase it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chase of desire, serving for it. Becoming servant. Servant for things we want, desires we have. Letting power to hands of desire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No desire, no power on others hands?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Better alter</title>
        <published>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-70-better-alter/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-70-better-alter/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-better-alter&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Better alter&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone shows we are wrong that means there is a better alternative. Being wrong is nice to discover. Being consistent forever is something stupid. Yes we don&#x27;t like being wrong. But we are already wrong. We were always wrong. We never learn the truth. There is no single truth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything we see and understand comes with our background, experience and knowledge in topic. When we start there was none. They put some ideas as default. Then we create life over it. But, who has a correct base to establish a life over it. Nobody! None of us can live a life itself. All is heritage. All is poisoned. All failures we have actually is nice to have to demolish and have a better alternative. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to where? I don&#x27;t know. We can not remove all life from our brain, it is not changing too much. It has alredy fixed in most fields of life. There just a little we can touch. Nice to see we still can. Nice to feel fresh air coming in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Slide</title>
        <published>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-69-slide/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-69-slide/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-slide&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Slide&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are in slide. Especially attention. It slides over bunch of things. It says in a point, sometimes for a long time like years, like all life. Imagine people with attention on people, events for a life. They never stayed on themselves, their own life, their own mind. Always checking outside and others.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of it, spending time and effort on things not yours, not related with you. Like spending to much time, money, effort on fixing a house that you rent. Isn&#x27;t it strange? Why people focus on things which are not themselves or theirs. Still strange. People are lost. Will never get a right touch to life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Lots of goods</title>
        <published>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-68-lots-of-goods/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-68-lots-of-goods/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-lots-of-goods&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Lots of goods&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People, people, people.. Annoying level of push. They value lots of things and apply pressure to me to give value, to count things good and chase. They even don&#x27;t know who they are, what they want. They just show each other, push each other. Then all becomes same, chasing same experiences, same things, getting joy from same things, liking same things, hating same things. What a ugly society! Who knows themselves truely? Who knows their true approach? One example is travelling. Why everbody loves travelling. Why they travel to same location next to each other? How can everybody love same thing? How can it be possible. Don&#x27;t you think it is a trap by media to drive economy?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiences, all are different. But name is same, show is same. Value is already given. And by all. I don&#x27;t know how they jump in same thing. Established in many years, from childhood; then you will never discover that why you fall in love. Is it love?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Opinion</title>
        <published>2024-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-67-opinion/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-67-opinion/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-opinion&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Opinion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He mentions a technique which i like and try to learn more about it. It is Cognitive Behavioural Therapy, means a lot more than this three words. It is clean, our mental process over the events on life. It is so clear that we shape the value of event and make it nice or bad. When we lose this key it starts to get shape by fixed view. Most of us has negative fixed view and if we do not pay attention to our mental process over thing our outcome will be sadness, anger, bad feelings because of our filter. Almost every event can be seen in a different way, most probably in a better way in life. But it needs cognitive effort over input to process properly and get a useful output. We forget that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Cost</title>
        <published>2024-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-66-cost/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-66-cost/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-cost&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Cost&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost i am paying ennoys me. Almost every day i get angry for it. It is totally unfair i think. But stoics says problem is me. Because everything has a cost in life. Every thing, every event, even being alive has cost. I can wait for a fair cost but why? Why should i create expectations from life and its people. I know it&#x27;s full of garbage. What kind of rule and system is going to give me my share and a fair cost for this life. Nobody can do that. It will always be chaos, random output, random people, random ideas. There is no point for being angry, it is so stupid. It is so stupid to get angry for a stupid life. There is no rule, no system to give a fair share. What kind of mindset drives you to have some expectations. I had removed expectations by focusing on my job. Now i don&#x27;t have job and focus is going to be shifted to random stuff. I need to focus on something like study, gym, reading, to keep me out of expectations trap. I need to work, study and stay busy. It is great.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Objective</title>
        <published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-65-objective/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-65-objective/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-objective&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Objective&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is objective. The perception we have. Life, events itself are just things around. They are objective. They  just happen. The issues comes with us, our judgement, our havy loaded feelings, expectations. We put the problem to things which are just there. And most of them are not from us, not to us, not related with us. We load them with our feelings, ideas. Leave them as they are. Consume events as they are, not mixed with feelings and weak points.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem that causes being stuck is not being humble. Not listening, not trying to learn. We can not learn without listening and proper approach. Even the most simple person may have a point which can improve our life. Can add a window to see things different, more clear, more fun, more and more. Try to listen. Most people have different ideas than yours. And different is better for a brain wants to innovate life. Not being stuck with same ideas, same feelings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Testing</title>
        <published>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-64-testing/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-64-testing/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-testing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Testing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we give something some value, especially some big value we test it. Think of money, we test it before change. But when it comes to ideas, feelings, thoughts we have, we don&#x27;t test them. We don&#x27;t check the source and value. It is crutial for our live but we underestimate and don&#x27;t test. Before getting angry, before getting excited give yourself 2 seconds. Test it, test the value, source and fact.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You remember old days, days with full of fast decisions, fast reactions, fast interactions of youthful days. Most were without wisdom and adequate judgement, testing. And most were the going to be regret for later. When you see yong people doing stupid things, you understand. They don&#x27;t pay attention, they don&#x27;t check, they don&#x27;t test the value and source. They just live instictively. They waste, they fill their body and mind with worthless things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Full of it</title>
        <published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-63-full-of-it/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-63-full-of-it/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-full-of-it&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Full of it&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes live is full of people, problems and combinations of them. We know it, we know very well. From beginning to end. It is same, it is full of them. But we forget, i don&#x27;t know how we forget why we forget, we forget that and start to get angry, get annoyed. Why?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we have one more problem. We are fast. Super fast to give opinion to pick a side, to judge. What kind of experience and wisdom we have? Why is this rush?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know life has poeple, people has problems, we have judgements. Great mix to create mistrust, misjudgement, misleading feeling. So easy to get annoyed, so easy to get angry, so easy to throw shit. But we forget us, we could keep calm for 2 seconds before planting anything. When you plant any feeling it is too late to remove, it will grow immediately. Give yourself 2 seconds before any kind of judgement and feelings. Don&#x27;t forget life is life. Full of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Verify</title>
        <published>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-62-verify/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-62-verify/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-verify&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Verify&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You tend to change when you get something, when you get money, when you get success. If you don&#x27;t pay attention you will find yourself changed. You have to verify the effect on you and the force of change. You should control it and shape the change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People will also give you some ideas and feelings. They may try or not they will shape and change you. Be aware, verify the people, the effect, the change, control it. Don&#x27;t let them to change to as they want. Don&#x27;t let anything shape you without your approval. Verify the input, verify the effect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Contradiction</title>
        <published>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-61-contradiction/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-61-contradiction/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-contradiction&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Contradiction&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is stange. Last time i have posted was two days aga i think. But it seems like it was 3 days ago. What is going on? I missed one day to count. How? Because i was in trouble with my eyes again. The computer touchpad is another problem. It is becoming like torture?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last page was on allowing people to reach us. How can you reach your goals with struggling poeples problems, sick ideas and issues. How can you move forward with listening their narrow, negative vision? It is impossible to move with this kind of people. We are stuck. No solution, no progress. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can you do with a brain full of negative, stupid ideas? What can you do with watching tv all day, scrolling stories one hour? What kind of input do you need to progress. The flow in your brain should be in same page as your dream. They have to match. They have to help each other and shape for better days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Unquestioned</title>
        <published>2024-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-60-unquestioned/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-60-unquestioned/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-unquestioned&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Unquestioned&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we, poeople are full of unquestioned behaviours and impulses. I have to question every think to decide for my days. Only then i will stand out, only then i will stop seeking impossible, the shortsighted and the unnecessary. What a good touch has this words! They are in chase of impossible because they didn&#x27;t question. They didn&#x27;t create dicipline. They didn&#x27;t see forehead. They didn&#x27;t try to see what is out, what is lost, what is gone, what is coming. I also don&#x27;t see the future, it is complex. But i have keep questioning, there is no other way to get out of mass. Mass like a dog chasing a car. Where are the questions?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And outlook, the mind full thought. Feeding itself, evolving every day. Like all systems, feedback shapes the system and response. How we shape our brains? By feeding. Feeding with negative ideas, negative feelings will cause a negative vision and create more negative feed. This is depression, this is how people stick with their trauma and problems. They become stuck there. Feed your brain with colorful, with open thoughts. Not desperate, dark ideas; with hope and light.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The plan</title>
        <published>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-59-the-plan-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-59-the-plan-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-cost&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The cost&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning i had no plan for the day. You may know that feeling, it is stressing, creating anxious mind and disturbs feelings. You don&#x27;t get into anything. Keeps you out. So i just grabbed my book and has written some words. I wrote i have apple, i have sandwich, i need to do toothbrush, i have bananas, i have cheese. Then decided getting tootbrush done and eating sandwich as breakfast. Kept the other part for dinner time. In which i would be working. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now i feel much better, brain has been cleaned by this plan and route. It is always useful. I don&#x27;t know how other people does but without a plan i can not leave home. I need a goal, even it is getting coffee i need to know what i am going to do. I know i have to leave home and i know i have to have a plan to do it. For everyday i need a plan to work, to live. Having plan is the best way of living day. Without even a small plan, days are just stressful to figure out what to do. We need reasons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The cost</title>
        <published>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-58-the-cost/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-58-the-cost/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-cost&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The cost&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sinop, a place with it&#x27;s happy people. Seems like future we wish. In past there was a famoues philosopher living there, Diogenes. Who reminds us the value, and the cost. The real one. He says big portion of things going to be overvalued and undervalued. People are not good in giving value. From his saying in thousands years ago to today, nothing has changed. We buy things, lots of things. We want to possess. We se poeple paying the value and we pay. But we are not good in this field. We always fail. You know what, if you don&#x27;t need something whatever you paid for it is expensive. Most of the things around have been thrown to us to buy, they are here not because we need. We buy them with ridicilous mind and judgement which poisoned by others, all other shit people. Stop. If they buy this is their problem, leave it. Value is not there, don&#x27;t give value. It is just cost, not value. Don&#x27;t mix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Greed</title>
        <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-57-greed/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-57-greed/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-greed&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Greed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed is sickness. It will eat you from inside. If you don&#x27;t have rational mind or suspend it, sickness will grow. It will empty all feelings you might have. It will capture you. Just an awaken, just a rational mind can regulate it, can stop it. Nothing can be like greed in destroying. It can destroy everything, all you have, all we have, all world have. Greed is total sickness, total sickness. Requires great attention. Don&#x27;t let it seed, don&#x27;t let it grow. Stay ratioanal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t forget, the day, the life is the field of experience what you have learned. You know if you always want more, fight, struggle for more, you will never get free. Greed kills freedom. Stay rational, stay free. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Ready</title>
        <published>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-56-ready/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-56-ready/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-ready&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Ready&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again Seneca, again great. Says that he doesn&#x27;t want war, he doesn&#x27;t like illness, but when it is here he wishes to do whatever he needs to do. To be ready to carry wounds nobly, bear all struggles, be ready.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, i am here again. Ready one more time for the day. It will bring some, no matter what. I am here. Wherever i go there i am. With all peace inside, all potential inside. With all inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the degree on the wall is my shoe which means i walk. All in. This is my way, one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Target victim</title>
        <published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-55-target-victim/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-55-target-victim/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-target-victim&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Target victim&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boss is frustrating, work is overwhelming? It seems like they are, but you are the one creating this perception and taking up these feelings. It seems like something from outside is annoying you, disturbing. But you are the one creating this and targeting them. They are just your target to blame, to throw guilty out. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Mello says, the cause of my irritation is not in the person but in me. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Dream life</title>
        <published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-54-dream-life/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-54-dream-life/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-dream-life&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Dream life&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My life, is a dream. It is dream of billions of people. More than 5 billion of people dreams for the life a have. I want to have my life. I live in a dream, most of dreamers will never get a life like this. I have a lot. The coffee, the sleep, the old friends, the book, the computer, the languages, the gym, the character and so on. I focus on problems and progress, this my style. But don&#x27;t forget what you have please. You have a dream life. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the taste, the value of it comes from labor. It is not free, no one gave me any thing. Except my frieds, everything i have is them, is from them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Gone</title>
        <published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-53-gone/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-53-gone/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-gone&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Gone&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They say yesterday is past, tomorrow is future. Today is a gift. That&#x27;s why we call it present. But i see the future, i live in a terrible future. It is not a healty and wonderful one. Today i went a store to change oil for car. When they ask my number, i couldn&#x27;t remember the half.It is my own number which i use everyday. The only number i keep in memory and use every day for coffee order. How can you forget something like this?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is gone. It is settled. Future is done. It has been with for a long time and taking root inside. One day it will be bigger than me and capture everything. Memories, friends, jobs, and persona. Don&#x27;t call me to fight, i am already in. And i am losing. I don&#x27;t know what is gone. But it is gone. All will be gone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Will of wrong</title>
        <published>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-52-will-of-wrong/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-52-will-of-wrong/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-will-of-wrong&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Will of wrong&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sokrates says, nobody does wrong willingly. It is not for all cases but covers huge part of life. He have seen the point. He knows people are doing their own right. Yes most of them following their own right and truth. But the problem is that everybody has a different background and logic. They end up in different assumstions. Most of them are different. So, when we see someone doing stupid, someone giving harm to us or other one, we think they are wrong. But they don&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a good attitude seeing people like this. All are following their own facts,  who knows what kind of inputs and issues they have. So, the things you see like mistakes, annoying you can not annoy you that much with this approach. It is their own internal process and facts. Not about you, most of time you can not touch their system. So, don&#x27;t exagurate, don&#x27;t take it personal. It is not to you, it is not for you, it is not about you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 3</title>
        <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-3/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-3/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-phrases&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about phrases&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;phrases&quot;&gt;Phrases&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braek down: to stop functioning
Call off: to cancel
Come accross: to find unexpectedly
Look after: to take care of
Bring up: to mention or introduce a topic
Go on: to contunie
Turn up: to arrive
Give up: to stop trying
Bring back: to return
Hold on: to wait
Take off: to remove clothing or to depart(airplane)
Set up: to establish or arrange
Get along: to have a good relationship
Look for: to search for
Put off: to postpone
Turn down: to reject or decrease
Give in: to surrender
Get over: to recover from
Look up: to search for information
Turn on: to switch on
Put up with: to tolerate
Break in: to enter unlawfully
Come up with: to propose or think of
Go through: to experience or endure
Catch up: to reach the same level
Take after: to resemble proudly
Show off: to display proudly
Pass away: to die
Point out: to indicate or mention
Bring about: to cause
Hold back: to restrain or withhold
Break out: to start suddenly
Carry on: to continue
Turn off: to switch off
Point out: to indicate or mention
Bring about: to cause
Check in: to register or arrive
Fill out: to complete a form
Run into: to encounter unexpectedly
Take up: to begin a hobby or activity
Turn into: to transform into
Back up: to support or reverse &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Friends</title>
        <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-50-friends/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-50-friends/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-friends&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Friends&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know i have a friend. She did my first and most important two tattooes for me. One is core on my neck, it is me. A man in action seems like running, cycling, riding, flying. Looking up and aiming high. As i like to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other tattoo is One Piece nakama on my right hand. The most important thing shapes me, gives the power and hope. My friends, they are the most important thing i have. Like friends setting a journey in One Piece, all connected forever, trying to find the One Piece. Which i think they already found.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a saying almost in all languages and cultures. It is like that, tell me with whom you consort and i will tell you who you are. I didn&#x27;t know this saying belongs to Goethe. But he has more. Says, If i know how you spend your time then i know what might become of you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let it be done, by you and by your source of power and hope. Which i missed a lot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Cato</title>
        <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-51-cato/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-51-cato/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-cato&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Cato&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, i was thinking about what kind of person am i. Why do i force myself to finish reading, writing, coding before opening browser and watching something. I know the reason, it is my core belief for labor. I have to deserve it, not just obtain. I know, free, cheap pleasure is our biggest enemy. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now i see someone in the book. His name is Cato, a Roman politician best known for his self-discipline and for his heroic defense of the Republic against Julius Caesar. He has no book, no letter, no lecture. But still here in book with his character. Seneca says we each have to have our own Cato, a great noble person we can allow into our minds and guide our actions. Adam Smith calls it indifferent spectator. Like i call it &#x27;future me&#x27;. Which a person cares me, knows more than me, experienced more than me and watchs me with me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Giving control</title>
        <published>2024-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-49-giving-control/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-49-giving-control/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-giving-control&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Giving Control&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do if someone touches your body, pushes, forces to somewhere to go. It is clear that noody likes it and nobody accepts this kind of things. But when it comes to mind, ideas, feelings, dreams, who has power on them. Do you thing you keep the control? Or is it shaped by social media, television, internet. Whats going on? Why we give them this right to have power on our own. We don&#x27;t notice but we give it volunteerly. It is totally self-inflicted. We do that, like letting them touch you, hit you, push you, grap you to somewhere. Why don&#x27;t we notice? Why don&#x27;t we take care of this power and keep with us. If you are going to park, why they grap your attention with notifications and throw you out of park? Why do you allow, why?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>See the game</title>
        <published>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-48-see-the-game/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-48-see-the-game/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-see-the-game&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) See the game&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the game. As Seneca says, no slavery is more disgraceful than one which is self-imposed. We are all in a trap. Think about power. Since then they have power? Since social media? Since television? Since cinema? Since songs? Since newspaper? Since books? Since sunday or friday prays?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see the game? Where do all these desires come from? Why do you have desires, wishes, dreams, surges? What is a person in birth? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is your future? How many steps of slavery will you climb or fall? Can you stop the rolling stone? Can you stay out? Is it going to smash everybody?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what they say, money brings money and power brings power. Can you imagine how they have grapped the power. Someone in young age defined a true path and pushed hard. They it has escalated through generations. Not like our story. We didn&#x27;t have someone knows the power, have access to it. What about being one?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Integrate</title>
        <published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-47-integrate/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-47-integrate/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-integrate&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Integrate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says it clear. We need to understand all about us and what is not about us. We need to integrate them. We need to understand and place them correctly. Over estimation and under estimation are both danger for us. You already have seen that you can handle most of the fears, you just keep yourself away by underestimating yourself and overestimating the fear. It has to be correct, otherwise all thinking, judgement, estimation is going to be problem for us. Failing is not that common like in our dreams and imagination. Most of the time we overcome the situation and smile for size of our fear in past. We see that they become part of history, solved, overcomed, succedded. Integration with our real true estimation would be great to keep going on our way. We need to know ourself, truely, all together. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Indifferent</title>
        <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-46-indifferent/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-46-indifferent/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-indifferent&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Indifferent&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regain your composure, it is waiting for you. It is you waiting there. You know yourself, all contaminants. You know who you are, and not is not part of you. Especially distractions, they are not part of you, may affect your composure but just in the case you allow. Do not forget your composure, yourself. All other things are indifferent, they are distractions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t ask for everything. Curb your desire, set your heart to a few things then you will get what you need. If someone says you can have it all, leave it. It is modern time mantra and totally wrong. Work, family, success, leisure, and blabla. Know what you want, truely want, truely need. Know it, instead of chasing desires. Ask yourself, forever, ask yourself. Define the things we are going to work on. You may do mistake, but you do for yourself. With your knowledge, it is yours. Ask, find, work on, update.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>React none</title>
        <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-45-react-none/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-45-react-none/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-react-none&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) React none&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaction is source of all good and bad feeling, judgements, decisions. But the problem we react everything, we label everything. What if i don&#x27;t label bad things immediately. I can have some time to thing, not just react and reach a result. Can leave it as it is, it will be waiting there until i label it. So why do you react everthing and cause lots of trouble? Leave it, don&#x27;t forget life is life. You don&#x27;t need to react everything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting back immediately is part of reacting. Most of it will come back to us as regret. Breaking heart is so easy in this way. But there is no repairment. You will have just regret. The reason is just reacting. You don&#x27;t need to do that. You can write down any kind of feeling and throw away the paper. This will heal your anger, sadness, depression and all other kind of bad feelings. You will be more calm, under control, moving without fast reaction, without breaking anything, without regret.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Desire of none</title>
        <published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-44-desire-of-none/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-44-desire-of-none/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-desire-of-none&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Desire of none&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was something i have learned after university and tried to apply. I was going to leave all desires, basic pleasures. I did well for a long time. Now i see same old saying from Diogenes, &amp;quot;It is the privilage of the gods to want nothing, and of godlike men to want little.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now i see, we need to have some of them. Some useful desires to place us in a point we want in life. If you kill all desires for what are you living? Leaving all desires is kind of rejecting yourself. And i also learned lately, &amp;quot;The biggest harm you can give someone is leaving he&#x2F;she alone&amp;quot;. Leaving them alone with their issues, struggles. Leaving them get eaten by desparation. Don&#x27;t do that anyone you love, don&#x27;t leave alone with desparate situations and feelings. This will create a swamp. And this kind of solitude will create a deepless one, you struggle alone, going worse and worse. Losing all hope day by day. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of people are not aware what&#x27;s going on. They will fail. But you know, don&#x27;t leave yourself to fall into this situation. Desire, hope, work and all other motiovations will carry you. If you don&#x27;t leave them you will not fall into swamp easily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Leave it</title>
        <published>2024-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-43-leave-it/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-43-leave-it/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-leave-it&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Leave it&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know how but people dislike their colleagues and putting that as an obstacle in their job. But you can not work like this. This is not the way. Why don&#x27;t you just be objective for job and judge things accordingly. Who said we need love to finish the job. Leave your all stupid ideas while handling a case. They should not block the path. Get rid of emotions which block the path, job is clear. Job is completed the tasks properly. Take care of it and go on without ugly feelings. They will never help. They will never improve performance. They will never solve any issue. They just block the brain, energy, work, life. All of them, all together.
What about conditional happiness? It is all we poeple have. Graduation, job, promotion, money, blabla. Yeah, where is horizon, can you ever reach there? You will never reach, because you will always have yearning for something, which will set your journey to horizon. A point you can never reach. Forget the reaching, you can never get closer. You can never get closer to happiness which is in horizon by set this mindset.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stop is nice</title>
        <published>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-42-stop-is-nice-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-42-stop-is-nice-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stop-is-nice&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stop is nice&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time we ask for pleasure as regular people. But i think there is another pleasure in rehecting the pleasure. It is not pain. It is pleasure of stoping chase, not following folks, popular and fency things. Even stopping during walk, listening a bird, walking slow, smelling a flower all are pleasure. There is a great pleasure for rejecting their pleasures. Which will become regret for most. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your mind is on charge. Do not find yourself in following stupid content, sensations and hormones. Stay away from people rashing like rats. Jumping from one thing to another, without any break to think.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many of things upseting us are coming from imegination not reality. People are in depression and stuck with bad imagination or reasoning. Don&#x27;t join them. The ideas and sadness will not be a solution. Solution is moving and doing something. Result will never be worse like imagined. Even you fail it will not be worse like imagined.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wake up right now instead of creating a nightmare. Do not allow the brain to continue creating bad imaginations, estimations, dreams. They are all imaginary and life it self will never be like that. Brain goes extreme levels, do not follow. Wake up, do something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Life change</title>
        <published>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-41-life-change/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-41-life-change/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-life-change&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Life change&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes were hurting again. When i push body limits it alwyas hits my eyes. I has droven 400 miles the night before, slept with burning eye, couldn&#x27;t rest and woke up at 7 AM, went to gym for a full body workout with a fast run. Then went to see city side by walk because car was problem with parking issues and my eyes were hurting. So my eyes are getting damage, vision is getting worse. Right eye is totally red now. I need some rest but haven&#x27;t get any since November. Now summer is coming with all heat and eye problems.
Is this the life i want? No,so i am here to write a little and code a little to heal myself and break this flow. I am not into this kind of life. I don&#x27;t want to waste my time and body with it. There is no time to be sad, or something else. It will not solve any problem. A change is must, a big change. 
I had some dreams full of disscussions about life. But i was in pain couldn&#x27;t write down them. After waking up from this dreams i decided to spent more time with people i care, with people i owe a life. When you live them their own in a bad situaion they become worse. Feel more useless, more weak, more lonely. My people are in trouble, getting worse. I know, this is the reason i am here. I need to open a door for a future. There was no way. Forgive me for all sacrifices.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hate and Anger</title>
        <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-40-hate-and-anger/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-40-hate-and-anger/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-hate-and-anger&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Hate and Anger&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcus was a true wise man. He says imagine the bad thing you don&#x27;t know. The things will make you sad, angry but you don&#x27;t know. You know you have a right to not have an opinion. You may stay empty, like not knowing. You will not have opinion, feeling over it. You will not place it. It will just pass. Seems a nice method. Choise of not having a idea, an feeling. Leave it there.
He says there is nothing like anger and hate which destroyed all around until they are only things remaning. Like a fuel, burns all other feelings, ideas and machine itself until it is the last one remaining and still burning. All anger, all hate we have leaves some burden in our machine, it will create huge mass in our system. Like my eyes. It is burden from old days. There was no mentor to stop me. The feelings were grasping me and eating a piece each time. Most ruins in the world has stories full of anger and hate. Maybe all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-38 Fear</title>
        <published>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-38-fear/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-38-fear/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-38-fear&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-38 Fear&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca says fear will destroy us and has potential to destroy everyting. Many great, powerful, succesful, smart people has destroyed all they have by fear. Thsy killed, betrayed their people because they had a terrible fear and were stuck with their idea. When you have just one idea in your brain every time you think about it you make it stronger. Because you don&#x27;t have counter ideas in your brain to create a balance and variety. If you are stuck with your fear and always think about it, it will grow and eat everything by starting from you. 
Like fear other extensive feelings and ideas has also no point. They just make the feeling bigger up to a point you can not handle. Sadness, regret, cry, anger all can reach great levels and block everything. Reaching high levels in these feelings will not help. You need to be aware and ask you that when you reach this point. Is this going to make better? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Thanks to Stanislav Petrov</title>
        <published>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-39-thanks-stanislav/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-39-thanks-stanislav/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-thanks-to-stanislav-petrov&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Thanks to Stanislav Petrov&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was a soldier on control of machine to detect missle attacks and respond. He has seen a rocket launch in screen. The duty to respond this attack and trigger nuclear missle launch. He didn&#x27;t. And waited to see, It was a signal noise in system. There was no missle coming. He disobeyed rules and didn&#x27;t launch attack. He saved all of us. Each live in the world. We have a peace is from his hands. Thanks Stanislav.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-37 Impulse and seek</title>
        <published>2024-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-37-impuses-and-seek/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-37-impuses-and-seek/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-37-impulse-and-seek&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-37 Impulse and seek&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic 36 was about impulses and control. Which we already wrote in some other topics. It says that we have people around us soaring highs and crushing lows. This the core problem for my family and much more others. This kind of people will seek top-high and waste all they have. If you are with them and even you are not part of it you will lose. Everthing, all you have can be destroyed by this kind of poeple. They don&#x27;t know what kind of impulse they have and how to filter them to choose the right one. I hate this approach, stupid impulses should not have this much effect on our lives. There is no justice in life, it is not fair. Totally unfair.
I am tried of these people. Terrified for their next step to use every chance for an idea, impulse they have. Total distruction of mind and life. Having a wasted life is hard. So hard. I am sorry for losing all. Now trying to protect me. There is no escape until end. End is too far. I don&#x27;t know how to get calm, how to control this anger, how to sleep in peace. I don&#x27;t know. Today I had my first white hair. Goodbye old memories, goodbye running like a crazy, googbye whistle on the sky, goodbye wind over the bike. Goodbye my dear friend, goodbye. We lost.
There is a note for Roosevelt. They say he was driven by something he has no control. It was addiction to work and activity. I think i understand him. I think he was escaping from something and that was the way. As he says &#x27;Being man in the Arena&#x27;. Seems crazy, seems stupid, seems endless. Book section 37 says this is wrong. But i understand, it was not choise. It was soul trying to espace. But if you don&#x27;t have something distroying everything, eating you from inside you will never understand. I did nothing wrong, didn&#x27;t hurt anyone. I didn&#x27;t deserve that. And there is no but. There is no espace, try to calm my dear old friend. Try to forget, you know i am good in forgetting. I will forget by default. My body knows the way, it will forget all. All i have, with its beauty. I am sorry my dear kind friend. Sorry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-35 Invincible Tone</title>
        <published>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-35-invincible-tone/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-35-invincible-tone/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-35-invincible-tone&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-35 Invincible Tone&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something i like a lot. My manager was a great example for it. He never gets angry. Always tries to understand and makes some jokes to make calm other person. But more importantly by laughing for a big crisis he helps himself most, then helps team. By seeing him laughing in a crisis we get more calm and think more clearly. And we always find something as solution, if there is not solution we accept the failure. He was the best manager i have ever seen. I missed him. He was already there, the point i want to be. In a level can handle any kind of people, with a wonderful touch and effect. A different kind of soul. I am lucky i always had a manager-leader i inspire. This is the way, i learn, adapt and develop. Not famly, friends we share some journey are our guide, our windows to world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-34 Anxious mind</title>
        <published>2024-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-34-anxious-mind-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-34-anxious-mind-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-34-anxious-mind&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-34 Anxious mind&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is really a topic which deserves a lot of reserch i think. Being anxious is part of life and going to dominate all of it. It seems like we spent our significant time by being anxious. It takes a huge part but what it is, why it is? We don&#x27;t ask this. We are anxious because we are weak, not prepared, not ready so not confident. I am anxious for the future, for the regrets i will have. Because i didn&#x27;t estimate them clearly, i don&#x27;t know what is on the road. I try to read, learn about others lives. To see matches between. But there are a lot of topics in life we get anxious. Like sports, like love, like job, like dans. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest reason we get anxious is lose of control. I think the more control freak a person get more anxious for unknown cases. I know i am kind of control freak, and most of the stress i have is because of it. There is a reminder in this section, he says: If we are anxious we need to understand that we are anxious about something outside, out of control, not in, not within. Getting worry about something out of control is not a stoic approach. We need stay awake and pay attention to us. To the things we can do, not the one we can not control. Let it to go. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-33 Not slave mind</title>
        <published>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-33-not-slave-mind-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-33-not-slave-mind-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-33-not-slave-mind&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-33 Not slave mind&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being independent and self-sufficient is biggest goal for most of us. We have these dreams and goal but don&#x27;t know the source of idea. Are we going to be happy because of us? Sad because of us? Who can decide our happiness and sadness. It is sound stupid and we fight to get the control. I am in same way, trying to hit these goals. But i think most of our push may be part of shit plan keeps us out of life. In the end we reach to same point. Most of us will have a happy life in last years. In happiness there will be not much difference. But this is just a possibility. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When i watch old people they are silent. I don&#x27;t know which one is full of regret, which one is hopeless, which one is happy. They don&#x27;t talk much and we do assumptions by looking their lives. Compare and grade. I think most of us will have a wasted life. We will be end of one journey, just one. The possibility of other options will eat us. We will always wonder for changes in past, regrets in past, fears and mistakes in past. If you are in the end, you will just have a past. Not future. The present you have is the only thing you live with. No options, no changes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they put their head to pillow, which people is happy for this life ? Which one thinks about memories. Most memories will be disturbed. They will never know the real taste of memory. I guess most people are trying their best to clear history, regenerate the memories in a way they can cope with. With reality, with the stupidity no one can survive. For me, it seems like i chase the freedom. Trying to get a warranty for future. But in future, i may have a life out of path and balance. And full of regret for paths i didn&#x27;t check. But i don&#x27;t think so. If i give up, everyday i will punish myself for giving up and reaching any kind of problems. Lets see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-32 Being hot headed</title>
        <published>2024-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-32-being-hot-headed-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-32-being-hot-headed-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-32-being-hot-headed&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-32 Being hot headed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says: the nearer a man comes to a calm mind, the closer he is to strength. What a great person is this Marcus Aurelius. What kind of emperor may have this wisdom to write it that clear! The writer is also a special person who digested all content and applied through life. He says &amp;quot;Remember, anger is not a power or strength. It is a mistake&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes anger is a mistake. I was always in that mistake for first two decades of my life. I didn&#x27;t know what is going on and no one has said that i am in a mistake which would cause my all problems. I think without that problem i would be a much better balanced person. The temper i had was enormous and distroyed almost everything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understood something about this wekaness by time and developed a better approach to life. When i get angry i remember the old days which caused just damage. Then i remind myself a question. Is it worthed to get damage for something you pissed of? Being calm, even cold helps to body for handling more easily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sorry my body. I was an idiot and didn&#x27;t know what was going on. I tortured you, caused wounds which will be with you forever. Forgive me body.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-31 Stop and heal</title>
        <published>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-31-stop-and-heal-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-31-stop-and-heal-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-31-stop-and-heal&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-31 Stop and heal&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a problem when to stop. I really wonder the answer. Cultures and backgrounds are totally different so people do different applications for life. Some never stops and pushes hard to reach a level. Some never pushes and just try to get joy. None is wrong, they just have different setup. But for me, i don&#x27;t know which i belong. Sometimes i decide to rest but i get regret for it. I could do something and make progress. It seems like i can never rest. I have work, i have to earn. Whenever i stop i lose, i go back. When should i stop, until when should i live in a restless life. As i know, in future i will be regretful for all stupid things and wasted time during these years. And the problem is that i don&#x27;t know what is right to do. If i manage to guarantee my future i will be happy to stop and rest. I know balance is must, stop is must, rest is must but the fear for regret in future is the biggest thing. Having a future in regret is terrible. I can not resolve this problem. I can not handle the result. Sorry. I need to work much harder than ever. I have to relief myself. I don&#x27;t want to stay in a prison a have created. Sorry, i am not able to have fun. I lost it. Like memories, friends, hopes. I wasted. What happens when you lose all friends? Most have family as friend, but what if you are alone? It has destroyed my soul and logic. I am not same person anymore. Sorry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-30 Turn off chase</title>
        <published>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-30-turn-off-chase-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-30-turn-off-chase-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-30-turn-off-chase&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-30 Turn off chase&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said i am lucky for my focus. I am also gladful for being away from mass, not following series, news, popular contents. I feel more free than most people. But this is my own effort, i put tons of effort to reach here. Other things out of my control is still in progress to mass with my life. I am tried, exhausted. It is hard to live without nothing. I missed them but i will keep myself on the road out of main steam. I struggle but i will resist keep going to see what is there for me. I think there should be something pushing me to this path. I am chasing anything. I just left all to see what is outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-29 Do your job</title>
        <published>2024-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-29-do-your-job-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-29-do-your-job-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-29-do-your-job&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-29 Do your job&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roman emperor says that we need to do our job or task as they are our lost. We should get rid of distraction and overthinking going on all around. We will place our energy and effort to just one thing at a time. This is a clear approach for a clean result and good job. Our lives are full of distraction and fields we tend to worry and consider possible outputs in all of them. This issue is getting bigger and wider for all people. Nobody can get focus in a job in a certain period. It is impossible for most people. I aggree with the approach and keep it with me. As they say in my work, i have a laser focus. It will be so hard to distract me. I am lucky, wish you a better day which you can focus on your job that you need to do. Do what you need to do; you have to do. There are times in life we can not waste. If you are still young, you know. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-28 Watch the wise</title>
        <published>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-28-watch-the-wise-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-28-watch-the-wise-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-28-watch-the-wise&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-28 Watch the wise&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is summer time and they set the temperature very low. It is cold inside, but i have to stay a little more to code and write. In book&#x27;s this section he touches a great point which i was thinking all night. Seneca says that without a ruler to do it against we can not draw a straight line. Thats totally right and matches with my concern. I think the problem most of us have is loss of mentor, the wise, the guide. In past families and reletives were more connected and i was possible to get guidance, feedback, mentorship from people we have. Now we last them. Personally i feel lack of it. This is why i have lost the path and come here. This is why i didn&#x27;t see whats going on around. I have been wasted in many ways, i wish i had a mentor which will stand there and warn me about life and things coming up. The lack of wise people caused all. For a short time in my life i had my elder brother as a wiser person, as mentor. But after years, connection got weakened. He set his own family, got more responsiblities, more importantly i reached a point nobody feels in same way and understands. Being alone in journel is not something healthy, it will end up with mass in most cases. The people has their father, mother as friend are the most lucky people around. Nobody can create a greater connection with you. I don&#x27;t know how it is but i think it is crutial for kids. As a observe people who has been lost, i think there was nobody around to keep them awake and on the right path.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-27 Put energy</title>
        <published>2024-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-27-put-energy-copy/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-27-put-energy-copy/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-27-put-energy&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-27 Put energy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t have access to computer every day. It is limited and i prefer spending this time with learning instead of reading, not even writing. But i promised myself i will do it. I need to catch, at least read all of them which can be useful in my life. The last page i have read is about essential fields i need to put energy and thougth. First field is what i like and dislike. Second field is what is my act, impulse, action. And last field is judgement. What is the reason. All are connected and shape day-life. Put energy and thought to them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-26 Back</title>
        <published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-26-back/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-26-back/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-26-back&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-26 Back&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am back to my old computer from 2019. Lenovo t490s, a missed one. I back to typing, after 8 months. The touch, the feeling is so deep. I have always been touching this keys like they have magic that going to give right for expression, right for search of truth, and control the result. I am back, back in control again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lastest page i have read from book was saying that we need to have a mantra, a sacred utterance, a strong saying, sound, word which will awaken us and remind the situation when we are trouble. Aurellius was suggesting that saying about &#x27;we are in control&#x27;. We decide what is going to enter and get effect in our mind, mood and life. We are in control, we are the one who will decide which input is going to shape our day and life. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By reading this part, i have remembered my old saying from last company. All friends were making jokes and showing respect to it. They liked so much, then copied my saying and started using in our meetings and discussions. When there is something out of control or any kind of problem with unexpected results, i was saying &#x27;Life is life&#x27;. All anger, all rush, all people with problem were placing properly with their value in life. Most were outer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was coming to me and explaining a situation and asking my opinion or approach for solution. Then just before i say something he was going with &#x27;You know what, life is life!&#x27;. I missed that man, one of rare, true friend. One of great fellow. (There is no &#x27;s&#x27;, he is true friend, he is fellow. He is one.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is life my friend, we are desparted and struggled a lot but you know we together did a lot. We will handle all, and meet. And we will say each other &#x27;You know what, after all, life is life. Again!.Back!&#x27;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Not a chicken</title>
        <published>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/not-a-chicken/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/not-a-chicken/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-not-a-chicken&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Not a chicken&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t think life should be like this&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life outside is different&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture is different&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is different&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Folks are different&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not a chicken&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&#x27;t have to stay here until you die&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave the cage&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live guys&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-25 The only prize</title>
        <published>2022-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-25-the-only-prize/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-25-the-only-prize/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-25-the-only-prize&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-25 The only prize&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire, the chase. They are huge problems which will cause us to be in a unstable, non-suffient situation. We need to control them. They have a prize, and it costs a lot. If we don&#x27;t know what to care most, we spend life and sources for something wrong. Something will not generate a better life. If you always follow basic desires the prize of that will be your life. The people who are aware and have a free, self-sufficient life are good example. Like Warren Buffet, he still lives in his old home from 1950s, car is also similar. This is the bahaviour we want. Being aware of priorities and applying actions accordingly will give us freedom. The more we buy, the more we obtain, the less free we are. We needs to find the cores and value them. Not others which will just keep us away from path and goal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-22 Day reviews</title>
        <published>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-22-day-reviews/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-22-day-reviews/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-22-day-reviews&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-22 Day reviews&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to the last day and results of it then designing a the new one with lessons learned will give us more reflection and more awareness for life and moment. Like CI&#x2F;CD, we continuously improve our life by tracking the problems and actions with their results. Perseverence is coming, for sure. Nothing can escape from continuous progress. When we look back, we should have mistakes there. It can be full of mistakes. Normal, we look to see and fix. We live for a better one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-23 The money issue</title>
        <published>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-23-the-money-issue/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-23-the-money-issue/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-23-the-money-issue&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-23 The money issue&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca was a reach man and say money is not solution. Self reflections and understanding needed, not money. He may be right but just up to some point. Too much money and some money may not differ for self realazation but no-money is really an issue and tough one. No money and too much money are extremely different and can shape whole life. So i can&#x27;t say money is not solution. It solves lots of problems. Then self issues begins. In this point, Seneca can say it is not effective enough. Yes it is not. After some point, the important thing is what you have harvested from life for your soul,body and mind. And the currency of this path is time and labour not money. For sure, we need money. And we need a good amount of it to have some self esteem, courage, and sustainable life. Then we start to discuss the details with out collection of knowledge, experience, feelings and thoughts. We raise with two bases, if one is weak the result will be weak, even ugly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-24 Learning Deep</title>
        <published>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-24-learning-deep/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-24-learning-deep/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-24-learning-deep&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-24 Learning Deep&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As wellknown by all, one of the most important skills in life is learning. Everybody has a great access to all kind of knowledge. They learn everything and sell it. You can see it everyday and everywhere. It is okay, it is part of modern life. But i like not learning everything in some amount. I like to be master in my topics. I think this is more important for my life and progress. The path i follow needs deep understanding and deep knowledge. And Marcus Aurelius mentioned that point in a note. He says don&#x27;t satisfy with rough understanding weak establishment. Poeple has a lot to say. Don&#x27;t get agree too quickly, try to get roots and cores.The way of reading this book is an example to deep study. We read just one page, we give us a day to think about and we write about it everyday. This is the way to get it completely and truly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-21 Morning rituals</title>
        <published>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-21-morning-rituals/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-21-morning-rituals/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-21-morning-rituals&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-21 Morning rituals&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the research, article and results says that all succesful people has something to do in their mornings. Some has meditation, some has exercise, some has reading, some has planning. The function is same, setting the body, the mind and the soul. Defining the problems of they and actions for the goal. By imagining the path and checking our path we become ready for the day through goal and path. Any kind of morning ritual helps. It sets us for the day. They are real solution for life. Solution comes day by day, step by step. Mornings are light over that steps.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-20 Ignite again</title>
        <published>2022-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-20-ignite-again/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-20-ignite-again/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-20-ignite-again&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-20 Ignite again&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It happens to all of us. We all fail and drift from our path. It is normal, it is part of journey. The fire seems so weak, like to fade and disappear. This fire is different, it is not that easy to vanish. It is the fire of life, the fire of will, the fire of hope. Fire of our soul, fire of our life, fire of our existence. We know how to set it again and again ever time. We did several times. We set great fires, hit great goals dispate of all obstacles and fails. The only thing we need stand up again again, ignite again and again. Burn and turn to future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-19 Adversity and Choise</title>
        <published>2022-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-19-adversity-and-choise/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-19-adversity-and-choise/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-19-adversity-and-choise&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-19 Adversity and Choise&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you already know most of people leave with adversity, with powerty, and struggles for a living. This is the background of most of us. We have lots of problems, issues, lack of essentials. But are living in luxury, power, and aboundance. Being in a condition like this and having hard times is part of this hard life. We can not change our history and background. So we can not complain. But we still have a right for our desicions. We can decide for our believe, act, knowledge and experience. We can experince the life as it is and move accordingly. We keep the the right and the power of decision maker of our life wiht us. After defining the path with a goal, working ahrd for it who cares the problems and history. We will do what we need to do and we will decide what to do. We have will. We will.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-18 Life poetry</title>
        <published>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-18-life-poetry/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-18-life-poetry/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-18-life-poetry&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-18 Life poetry&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To smell a flower we need to stop. We need to look around and find. The taste will find us itself. We will stop, search for it, find it, and get enjoy from life with this way. This is the way. Just passing through, just rushing will give us nothing. To catch, to create mean and taste we need to have a vision based on this wisdom. We need to look around different. Without search no one will find any taste from life. Change your vision, perspective to gather beauty from moments. Like writing a poetry, without different view no one can write it. Seeing the beauty requires a different-active look. Look around alive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-17 Start</title>
        <published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-17-start/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-17-start/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-17-start&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-17 Start&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, Epictetus was a great teacher in his time. And he says us to start. He says that we have a great teacher and his word. Hw knows very well. We can believe him. The only think we need to do is starting. We will believe him and start. Start, then you will see. It will happen. Just start.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-11 Serenity</title>
        <published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-11-serenity/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-11-serenity/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-11-serenity&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-11 Serenity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, i didn&#x27;t know the meaning of serenity. It is like calm, almost same. I think serenity is a little more than calm. It requires a calm mindset and mature phiolosophy. As you can see from date of this post i didn&#x27;t read and write for 10 days. I was working so hard and coming home just for sleep. I continued for weekend even in a worse level. I couldn&#x27;t sleep and couldn&#x27;t think healthy. So it makes a deadloop and blocks me to go out of circle. This is so common. When you are out of circle, you discover that time has past and life is gone. It is to far and it is to late to catch it. So having unbrekable rules to return yourelf, to return your system and path is crutial. It is not just a piece, it is bundle. Each piece has a function and they work together. In my bundle there is walking, running, reading and exercise. Last week i did non of them and it was terrible. All bundle was lost and there was nothing to recover me and refresh the progress. My obsession for work and duty comes before everything and this is the root cause of this unbalanced, out of control situations. I have to stay calm and keep serenity with me in this kind of situations. Serenity will be reward if i manage. But serenity is also cause, the method for a proper approach. I should always keep in mind that question. Where is my serenity, where is my peace and where is my life? This will help to stay away from distructions. Life, people and company is so big and they will keep going in any condition. Don&#x27;t force yourself to change them. They are out of control, even if you are inside, no your effect is almost nothing. Save your life. Do not waste for this kind of obsessions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-12 Control Circle</title>
        <published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-12-control-circle/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-12-control-circle/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-12-control-circle&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-12 Control Circle&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal and the beginning were so clean. But i am getting far step by step. Consistancy is really hard in this life. As i learned very lately, there is no talent. It is consistent dense effort through something. Consistancy is the real essence of success and progress. But as you see it is really hard. I don&#x27;t know how hard it is for other people. I think it is much more harder. This brings us to the topic. It was one week ago but i still remember. The circle, the control over the circle is not an option. Circle means the poeple, the environment, the body, the possesions all surrounding around our mind. Even the most closest one, the body is out of our control. We cannot control them. The thing we can control is how we think about them and what we care. When we care the circle and try to control or change it, we are going to mix and mess up with control circle. Mind is our single circle we can control, all other circles and related issues are our. We need mind the inner circle not all circles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-13 Cutting Attention</title>
        <published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-13-cutting-attention/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-13-cutting-attention/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-13-cutting-attention&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-13 Cutting Attention&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic is attention. We always thing we have time and they are trying to get our time. But behind time there is something more important and covers all fields.It is attention. Nowadays everything is trying to get our attention. This is our main source and base of our time. Be aware and be careful about what you pay attention. If it is not from you, it means you are targetted. Attention is the source drives us through something. And also pull us to reach there. Set a proper attention and be aware of it. Don&#x27;t spend it for out sourced trigger and attractions. Use your attention wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-14 Peace on path</title>
        <published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-14-peace-on-path/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-14-peace-on-path/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-14-peace-on-path&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-14 Peace on path&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca calls it as euthymia. It means knowing your path, knowing yourself and believin. This will bring the peace. The peace of being on the way, being on the process. The most beatiful peace is this kind of peace. By peace and progress it becomes more clear in our vision and understanding. This will make the days more full. Thefulfilment coming from path and peace, life will bemuch more satisfactory. Keep yourself in path and progress. Don&#x27;t get distraction and don&#x27;t get lost with jumping new-attracting ideas. Stay alive, not a jumping frog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-15 No auto acts</title>
        <published>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-15-no-auto-acts/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-15-no-auto-acts/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-15-no-auto-acts&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-15 No auto acts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We live in a style which we don&#x27;t consider much about what we do, how we do and why we do. We spend most of the time and also life with auomated actions even without noticing them. It seems most of people is like this and life spreaded around world is unnoticed and wasted unconsciously. We need to keep eye on our time, action, ideas, behaviours. They shouln&#x27;t be out of habit. We need do what we do for our purpose and properly. We need to aware that we spend our life and our energy for something which serves to goal and has nice outcomes. A wasted life is just a waste. Don&#x27;t cause a wasted life keep it a life. Stay alive. Live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-16 Remember choices</title>
        <published>2022-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-16-remember-choices/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-16-remember-choices/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-16-remember-choices&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-16 Remember choices&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We usually forget that faith, life, nature and all others things has their own rthym. We don&#x27;t have control over their flow and we get affected unconsciously. We can not control that effects on us and our life. They will decide for lot s of thing and they will shape the most of things. We have a very limited field which we can apply some rules and actions. It may not work but we have just some choices. We are off that. We have choices. This is almost everything we have. Don&#x27;t forget that you have no control over most of things. But, we live and depend them. For instance, we sleep.To go sleep we trust the surrounding, nature and all others. We leave the control. It was always out of control but were always trusted. So, we control what we can and leave others. Remember you already trust a lot the life out of control. Don&#x27;t worry for this part. Live your part, your choices.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-10 To be in unsteady</title>
        <published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-10-to-be-in-unsteady/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-10-to-be-in-unsteady/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-10-to-be-in-unsteady&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-10 To be in unsteady&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We said we need to have a stable brain and structure inside in last post. But now let&#x27;s make one thing clear. We also need to jump in to the unsteady cases and situations. Old Stoics were all in playgorund, in field, in military, in marketplace. We also have to be in field and experience problems. There is no way to solve problems by running and hiding. The single way to get rid of problems is facing them. Not hiding, ignoring, rejecting. They discomfort us, they terrify us, they disturb us yes. We are trying to stay far and safe. But this is the nature of problems. They will cause issues forever if we don&#x27;t solve. Even we don&#x27;t like, even we don&#x27;t have experience we need to be in uncomfortable, problematic situations to overcome them. At least we will get used to and in next time we will know the nature or the situation. By this adaptation, even we don&#x27;t solve it we will be stable and steady in further experinces with same problem and situation. Then this calm nature will give us a better condition to get along with them. It will be more easy to be there longer and jump to solve. Don&#x27;t hide and run from problems. Jump in and struggle, you will see how you adapt and tackle them. Or live with them if they are impossible to solve.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-9 To be stable</title>
        <published>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-9-to-be-stable/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-9-to-be-stable/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-9-to-be-stable&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-9 To be stable&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was kind of abstract topic. It is hard to remember the name and content. It says we need to create proper filters for us. They will be our base and will be used for judgement. We will not take inputs directly, instead we will select the correct one, the useful one for us. We will filter incoming things, and keep our system stable and on going. Otherwise the random and messy input will create garbage insidde even can cause corruption in some ideas, feelings and actions. Inputs we have are very important and our single option to get feedback from life to improve it. The input have to be proper. Be selective for the inputs. Do not get garbage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-8 Control freakness</title>
        <published>2022-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-8-control-freakness/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-8-control-freakness/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-8-control-freakness&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-8 Control freakness&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we-people assume that life is ours. This is our life and we will make it as we like. We try to control whatever we can to reach our goal, to reach our desired life. Life is for us and we should be able to control and push it to the point we want. But, life is not for us. Life is not ours. We control almost nothing. We change almost nothing. Life is there and keep going, even without us. We have no control almost anything. We have just a very small amount of control on our some ideas and behaviours. The thing we can do managing and shaping them, nothing more. Put effor to the things you can change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-7 See addictions</title>
        <published>2022-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-7-see-addictions/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-7-see-addictions/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-7-see-addictions&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-7 See addictions&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spend lots of time every day. Most of it is used for very small not recognised things. We all have lots of addictions. They repeat always and get a big partition from our life. Usually when we discover them it is too late. Because they are hindered in daily life. To recognise them we need to stop, think, and search them. If you find yourself doing something please thing about it one more time. Is this thing for your goal and plan? Why you are in that accupation or addiction. Like finding yourself watching youtube, or eating nails or snacking or blablabla. It can be any kind of it and it take great time and effort from our life and goals. Discovery of addictions will open our eyes. In next time you may stop yourself before jumping to that addictions. Remove them, create space for yourself, and put proper action and habits as replacement. Otherwise they will come back if you keep your time empty. Fill your time with proper steps. You have goal, don&#x27;t forget. Don&#x27;t waste life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-6 Core steps for days</title>
        <published>2022-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-6-core-steps-for-days/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-6-core-steps-for-days/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-6-core-steps-for-days&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-6 Core steps for days&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have listed some steps to apply. It is so didactive and straight. I think i don&#x27;t like this kind of content and it will not take place in my memory. As a result i have nothing to write about this page. This kind of knowledge is not open to think and write about. I will skip this page. Actually they are not daily actions, they are functions of mind. But let me list them before go:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choice&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refusal&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yearning&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repulsion&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preperation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purpose&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assent&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-5 Who where why</title>
        <published>2022-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-5-who-where-why/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-5-who-where-why/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-5-who-where-why&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-5 Who where why&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to ask so questions and think about some core values. Who we are, what are we doing, why are we here, where are we heading. Know yourself, your life, your nature. If you don&#x27;t, no one can know and guide through life. You need to know yourself to guide properly, to understand and manage correctly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-4 Know the path</title>
        <published>2022-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-4-know-the-path/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-4-know-the-path/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-4-know-the-path&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-4 Know the path&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section has reference from two great book, one is 48 Rules of Power, other one is 7 Habits of successful people. With this book, these three great books say the same thing: Set the end = Set the goal. I refer it as &#x27;know the path&#x27;. All have same core idea and saying that we need to know our destination. By this knowledge we can see the path and also we can see what is going to help in this path and what is not going to help. Otherwise we will be like a ship without route. We never reach the right destination. The place we go will be random one and defined by others. If you don&#x27;t know your path, goal, end, destination whatever it is, you have no chance to reach there. Directionless is terrible for this life. We have to have and make it clear. Everything will be aligned if you know where are you heading and you make decisions accordingly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-3 Saying No</title>
        <published>2022-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-3-saying-no/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-3-saying-no/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-3-saying-no&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-3 Saying No&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third component in the book is about saying no. We have goals and paths through our life. We will always find something staying on the road and blocking our progress. They can any kind of feeling like anger, anxiety, depress. We need to say no to them and their sources, to people causing them. To people asking for something whichwill keep us away from our target. Don&#x27;t lose your path,be aware of obstacles and misguiding. Say no to misguided feelings, wasted time and blocked paths. Say no to anybody is going to cause them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-2 Education is freedom</title>
        <published>2022-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-2-education-is-freedom/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-2-education-is-freedom/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-2-education-is-freedom&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-2 Education is freedom&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As i promised, i will write about the topic everyday. This is the second one. It was about education and freedom. He says education is freedom but not as a feature. By purpose. We have lots of options which are much easier than reading. We do reading to learn, to be more resilient to fears. Education is the wayto handle the lack of knowledge and fears. So education is the way of freedom. It is not freedom itself, it has the purposeof freedom. It is by purpose.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Stoic-1 Control and Chaos</title>
        <published>2022-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-1-control-and-chaos/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/stoic-1-control-and-chaos/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-stoic-1-control-and-chaos&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Stoic-1 Control and Chaos&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching a person in youtube. His name is Ray Holiday and the channel is daily stoic. In one of the videos he mentioned about writing andhow many books he has written by just being consistent. It seems like enough to create a basein our life. He suggests that to write journal every day. For this goal he has published a book with questions to answer and guide us every day. Then i decided to buy this book but during search i have discovered he is the writer of The daily stoic:366 meditations on wisdom, perseverence and the art of living. I decided buying this book first. This post is my first writingfor the first topic in the book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It says the wisdom starts with understanding what we can control and what we cannot. If we stop worrying about the things we cannot control and put our effort and energy to the things wecan control we fullfill a lot. Other way around seems like waste. As saying says:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God grant me the serenity to accept the things i cannot change, the courage to change the things i can and the wisdom to know the difference.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection of the things we will think and put effort is first step. This is core for a more resilient life and character. We cannot take distance with much distraction which is mostly by purpose. Pick the things you can control and change. Do not overthink and distur yourself with the stuff you cannot change, you cannot control. Welcome to the core of stoic lifestyle. Suffering is okay, but for the right thing. For the thing will carry you to the next point. Don&#x27;t spent much time in past and also future. Today is same day. It is one of days which brings us here. Not past not future, today will give the life, today will shape the life. Don&#x27;t focus others, keep your focus on today. On the thing may change the results.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Song lyrics</title>
        <published>2022-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/song-lyrics/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/song-lyrics/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-song-lyrics&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Song lyrics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is to die&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is to live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is surronded with them&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The resistance</title>
        <published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-resistance&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The resistance&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no rule and order in context and title. They are just a piece of my daily feelings, experience, and learning progress.
Today I have just decided to write about resistance. Because yesterday I couldn&#x27;t start to write.
I wanted but there was no idea and motivation. Creating a habit is always hard because we are not able to see the future and end of our path.
We may feel satisfied but also we can regret it after spending some years. When we force ourselves to do what we don&#x27;t want we treat ourselves like a maid.
At this point there should be a border, we shouldn&#x27;t tyrannize ourselves and should find a way and create a tactic to keep us on our way but also
train us by having tough times. We need to evoke ourselves in a way and see what we are doing. Otherwise, it might be too late for decisions and change.
There is no exact truth but searching and having a meaning and goal will be helpful for the future.
To develop our credibility we should look to people who have a better life and read about their lives so we can decide more wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exact&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;satisfied&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;credibility&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;channel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cassette&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;habit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tactic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evoke&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The fact of dream life</title>
        <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-fact-of-dream-life/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-fact-of-dream-life/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-fact-of-dream-life&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The fact of dream life&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no time in which everthing would be done and you will start to live. Rest in peace with your desires and dreams. Or live this day before passing..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The goal and way of writing</title>
        <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-goal-and-way-of-writing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The Goal and way of writing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method is very old. We all get lessons about it but we don&#x27;t pay enough attention because writing is a boring activity for children. So we grow up without improving this skill enough. After some years of experience in business and also communication paths in daily life we understand how important is the usage of language and richness in vocabulary. Now we all know that communication skills and consistency are the most important skills in life. So, we need to improve ourselves in these skills. According to Jordan Peterson, we need to write more and more to use the language more effectively and order our ideas to think more clearly and properly. By that time I have been thinking about consistency and effective ways of getting this skill. By getting an impression from the homework the teacher gave us and suggesting to do more, I decided to write consistently, almost every day. These two activities will be a perfect fit for lots of problems especially are related to personal identification, communication, and expression. The way of doing this is by defining 10 random words and using 6 of them in a context. Cooperation by others will make it more interesting, interactive, and also more effective. Because seeing others&#x27; writings about the same words will improve our creativity and our own writing. The rhythm we have and keep for that habit will define our progress. When we execute this plan well we will get lifelong durable and very important skills. Otherwise, we will be in the case of resigning ourselves to the lives we don&#x27;t like because of weak character and personality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identification&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resign&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cooperation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amputate&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diamond&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rhythm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;execute&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rugby&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 2</title>
        <published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-2/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-describing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about describing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catchy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : memorable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;commercial&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : converned with or engaged in commerce&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;disturbing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : causing anxiety; worrying&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dull&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : lacking interest or exciment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gripping&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : firmly holding the attention or interest; exciting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hilarious&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : extremely amuzing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;over-the-top&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : to an excessive or exaggerated degree&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uplifting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : inspiring happiness, optimism or hope&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;weird&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : uncanny&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sentences&quot;&gt;Sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It didn&#x27;t do much for me. It&#x27;s very commercial.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is just too much for my liking, really over-the-top.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does nothing for me. It&#x27;s quite boring, quite dull.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: What kind of thing do you do in your free time?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: I guess the films are the main thing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: Really. Do you go cinema much then?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah. I mean it depend&#x27;s what&#x27;s on.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;m happy just to watch at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t you want to see it on the big screen?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be honest, I am not that keen on action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suppose, I&#x27;d rather see other things.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was so over-the-top. That scene where he eats the live octopus! It was all a bit too weird for my liking.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C: As I said, it is not really my kind of thing. So what other films are you into?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D: Oh all sorts. (every type!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;m really into action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;ve heard it is good. I was actually thinking of going to see it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought it was supposed to be a feel-good movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did they think of them?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;disaggrements&quot;&gt;Disaggrements&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess but &lt;strong&gt;to be honest I&#x27;m not that keen on&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was all &lt;strong&gt;a bit too&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; weird &lt;strong&gt;for my liking.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I say, it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;not really my kind of thing.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was not bad, &lt;strong&gt;I suppose but ..&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often soften responses by using phrases such as &lt;strong&gt;I&#x27;m not that keen on, I guess, I suppose, to be honest, for my liking..&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We also use &lt;strong&gt;a bit&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to soften negative adjectives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;quotes-about-art&quot;&gt;Quotes about art&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art is the lie that enables us to realise the truth.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art is what you can get away with.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urge of destroy is also a creative urge.(&lt;em&gt;urge: impulse, desire&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more minimal the art, the longer the explanation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art never responds to the wish to make it democratic; it is not for everybody; it is only for those who are willing to undergo the effort needed to understand it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;descriptive-sentences&quot;&gt;Descriptive sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold colours are very bright, strong and clear, whereas subtle colours are not strong or bright. They&#x27;re softer and more delicate.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  delicate: (fine, elegant) very fine in texture or structure, of intricate workmanship or quality. Ex: A spider&amp;#39;s web is stong yet delicate
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  subtle: (fine-drawn, ultra-fine, elusive) so delicate or precise as to be difficult to analyze or describe. Ex: His language expresses rich and subtle meanings.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a painting is &lt;strong&gt;conventional&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, it&#x27;s traditional and not new or different in any way.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  conventional: based on or in accordance with what is generally done or believed.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;atmospheric&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, a painting creates a special mood - such as a feeling of romance or mystery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;ambiguous&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, the meaning of the work isn&#x27;t clear - it&#x27;s oepn to interpretation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;intimate&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; painting shows private moments in someone&#x27;s life.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  intimate: closely acquinted, familiar, close. (as noun: a very close friend)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main character has his back to the viewer, which creates a feeling of mystery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;looks as if&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; he&#x27;s thinking about killing himself.(as if + sentence)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He is &lt;strong&gt;obviously&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a sad and lonely man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the most important thing in the painting. Ex: The car &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be running well. Everyone &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; have thought the same thing. He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; know the facts. This house &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be empty. He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be losing. She &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be sad. That &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the hardest word I&#x27;ve learned. It &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be working, though I don&#x27;t know for sure. It &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be good. What &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the problem here? She &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be losing her mind.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;appears to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be looking for something better than what he was.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He looks very proud. I get the impression he feels very pleased with himself.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;looks like&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a very wealthy man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be someone in Europe. It &lt;strong&gt;could well&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be France.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who do you think people in there might be?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you think they&#x27;re feeling?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What might the connection between the two works be?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what way are two paintings connected?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what way might the viewer&#x27;s first impression of the paintings be wrong?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sentences-1&quot;&gt;Sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow me &lt;strong&gt;through into&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the next room.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died &lt;strong&gt;at the age of 37&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;at a time&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; when his career was going well and since then he has been forgotten, which &lt;strong&gt;seems to a bit of a shame&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, to be honest.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These two paintings were meant to be hung together as &lt;strong&gt;companion&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; pieces.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  companion: a person or animal with whom one spends a lot time with whom one travels
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He was &lt;strong&gt;composing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the letter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  compose: write or create (a work of art, especially music or poetry).Prepare (a text) for printing by manually, mechancally or electronically setting up the letters and other characters in order to be printed.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She is &lt;strong&gt;digesting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  digest: break down (food) in the alimentary canal into substances that can be absorbed and used by the body.(sindirmek)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His surroundings create the impression that he&#x27;s well travelled.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He&#x27;s man of the world.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woman seems to belong more to the domestic world. She looks calm and &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; as she reads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  content: a state of peaceful happiness
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, not everything is as it first appears. &lt;strong&gt;Beneath&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the surface of the calm domestic world lies trouble.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  beneath: at a lower level or layer than
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously, the woman was so excited to receive her letter that she jumped up in the middle of her needleworkk.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;could well&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be a symbol of the difficult, stormy nature of love, especially when partners are seperated. There is another letter to deliver, &lt;strong&gt;presumably&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even he, &lt;strong&gt;depicted&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in darker, more subtle shades, is a victim of the fires of the heart. The rich red of carpet and the bright &lt;strong&gt;light pouring&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in through the window suggest he has a &lt;strong&gt;heated mind&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.(angry and excited)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  depict: show or represent by a drawing, painting, or other art form
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underlying message now seems &lt;strong&gt;painfully clear&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: passion can lead to chaos.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  painfully clear: it is embrassing because it is so clear&#x2F;obvious&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 1</title>
        <published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-1/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-1/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-entertainment&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about entertainment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do you think the place is?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you want to read in a place like this?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you usually take a book with you when you&#x27;re travelling or do you prefer e-book readers?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&#x27;s the nicest or most unusual place that you&#x27;ve spent time reading in?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you read much?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-answers&quot;&gt;Example answers:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like all kinds of stuff as well -rock, pop, even some classical.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t tend to during the week, though, because I&#x27;ve got to get up early and basically my parents prefer me to stay at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as much as I&#x27;d like to, because I really love it - especially musicals. The seats are so expensive I can&#x27;t afford to go more than a couple  of times a year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find it a bit boring. It&#x27;s not really my kind of thing and I&#x27;m not very good at it either.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably less than I think I do. It&#x27;s always on in the background, you know, but I don&#x27;t pay much attention to it most of the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will watch a big game if there2s one on and the occasional film, but apart from that, most of it&#x27;s rubbish.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah, I guess so. I generally cycle to college as well -unless it&#x27;s raining.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend to watch films on demand through my TV at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as much as I used to.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now and again   -   ?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tend to     -&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;habit-s-grammer&quot;&gt;Habit&#x27;s Grammer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;past&quot;&gt;Past:&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk about past habits, we can use the past simple, used to + infinitive(without to) or would + infinitive(without to). Examples:&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listened to music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used to listen music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;d listen to music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;present&quot;&gt;Present:&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk about current habits we can use the present simple, tend to + infinitive(without to) and will + infinitive(without to)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listen to music all the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend to watch films on demand through my TV.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;adverbs-and-adverbal-phrases-for-frequency&quot;&gt;Adverbs and adverbal phrases for frequency:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;always, all the time, constantly&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;normally, usually, as a rule, one the whole, by and large&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes, now and again, once in a while&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;almost never, very rarely, hardly ever, once in a blue moon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not as much as  + I&#x27;d like to &#x2F; I want &#x2F; I used to &#x2F; I did before&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-negatives-for-habits&quot;&gt;Making negatives for habits&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can make negatives with tend to and used to in different ways.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&#x27;t use to like it very much.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I never used to listen to music at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend not to go to the cinema that much.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mistakes&quot;&gt;Mistakes:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t say &lt;em&gt;use to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about habits in the present. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;use to&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;usually&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;tend to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; go out with friends on a Friday.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use the past continuous to talk about past habits. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;was going&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;went&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;used to go&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; swimming a lot when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use &lt;em&gt;would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about character and other kinds of states. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;would have&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;had&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;used to have&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; long hair when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use &lt;em&gt;how&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; instead of as in comparatives. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t go as much (&lt;del&gt;how&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;as&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I&#x27;d like to.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;did-you-know&quot;&gt;Did you know?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is actually far more common than &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about past habits. That&#x27;s because while we often introduce a topic with &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we tend to give details with &lt;em&gt;would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Ex:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;used to make&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; my own films when I was younger. &lt;strong&gt;I&#x27;d watch&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; famous films and get ideas and then my brother and I &lt;strong&gt;would try&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to make our own versions. &lt;strong&gt;We&#x27;d then do&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; screenings for our family.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;Ex:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By and large, I don&#x27;t tend to watch TV much. There are too many ads, which annoys me.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t see her as much as I used to, because we&#x27;re both so busy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Golden halfmoon</title>
        <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-town&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Town&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town we will talk about is Halfeti. It is part of the city named Sanliurfa which is famous for being the source of religion in the world. In my country, we call this city the city of prophets. Because lots of prophets have been there during history, like Muse, Abraham, Elyasa, Adem, Ayub. And also a temple named Gbeklitepe dates back to 9500 BC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During endless stream of time, the city managed to survive in mandatory of different countries. In this matter, the town Halfeti has a unique position in one respect. It has a castle in the middle of the river which were defining the border of the Eastern Roman Empire. When you see the picture of the castle you see how fairly reasonable to build it there. It is like the wall in the game of thrones. Because the river still defines the east in Turkey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pass the west side you should pass across the river. Besides, according to the book Homo Sapiens, the River Euphrates defines the Fertile Crescent with another river named Tigris. The region around these two rivers was very productive and important during history so the agriculture, religion, and writing were sourced from Fertile Crescent. Nowadays, the situation is slightly different. Rivers are still very important but industries were not established there. Despite being so historic they don&#x27;t have enough amenities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Halfeti people has a living just from agriculture. The discovery of the first temple of the world in Urfa started to attract tourists. Moreover, having a sub-merged town under the river makes the Halfeti attractive for tourists. Some parts are photogenic but it was a ghost town when I was a child. Nowadays, it is a lively town with sailing, canoe, and diving amenities. There are not many residents and no imposing buildings. Also, because of the narrow streets, I suggest that to leave your car on the main road and walk. Because it is a Cita Slow with a gentle rhythm and a self-contained environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The middle man</title>
        <published>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-middle-men-and-old-man&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Middle men and old man&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle. Middle of what? Who knows? He always felt like this without any idea for reason. He was brought up in a conservative family that potentially was in the heart of his life. But he doesn&#x27;t want to remember those days anymore. He knows how he felt after expelling from school and being like on the ledge of family. His father was like a sheer wall for every discussion and preventing him to shape his own way. Maybe that was because of buzzing news about war and the bad economy, but there should have been more. He has never known that. Because, after staying in the zone and hard working he got the foot in the door of university and left them behind. He hasn&#x27;t looked back after this moment and flashed around the country with his exam scores. Everyone was stunned because it was impossible to work flawlessly in that conditions. It was merely a small possibility to rally after this long period of indolence life. But they had forgotten how greasy he is for his decisions and after deciding to his way how hard to change his mind. Now he was at the summit of Mont Blanc and has just signed the summit book. He was standing on his planted steps with an old feeling like being in the middle of a low surrounding.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle of foreigners. They had come from far but he was from the city. Unlike others, he felt fatigued in the middle of the way but he rallied by staying in the zone and pushing towards his limits. In the end, these bad feelings turned into being stunned due to the accomplishment of this goal. Because it was a merely impossible dream for someone at that age. After he explained his decision, all family members warned him about how this event potentially can kill him. They said that he was in the heart of the family and he shouldn&#x27;t do that. However, it was not true and he has felt like he is on the ledge of the family until this moment. Now he was standing over planted steps in the summit. This was the point he got his foot in the door of climbing and became the oldest person who climbed to Mont Blanc. The news was buzzing this journey and it flashed around the world.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man was fainted due to lack of sleep and fatigue. Because he had already been sick. Writing and staying in the zone for several hours was potentially dangerous. The doctor and all family members warned him but after getting his foot in the door of writing he became more undeterred and it was impossible to dissuade him. He was a famous writer and had flashed around the world once upon a time. So, even getting stuck in some points he rallied to finish this book before the party. The book was supposed to be a birthday gift the next day. There was merely a small time before the party and the book was finally completed. Everything was working flawlessly according to his plan. The girl would be stunned when she saw the book had written for her. The old man closed the book and named it by using one of the greasy tags. He wasn&#x27;t aware of the broken door ledge and also that the name will have been buzzing in the news the next day. Because it was the last book of a great writer who was at the summit of his career. During his long and successful journey, he hasn&#x27;t looked back but it was time to rest last time. By this book, an old saying is brought up again. There is no reward without taking risks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;by listening rock&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Podcasts</title>
        <published>2019-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2019-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/podcasts/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/podcasts/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-tr-list-of-the-best-podcasts&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng-Tr&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) List of the best podcasts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of the best podcasts I have listened so far. I will update this list as I listen more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before my list, Lets see the best podcasts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-best-podcasts&quot;&gt;The best podcasts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;podcasts.joerogan.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Joe Rogan Experience&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tim.blog&#x2F;podcast&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Tim Ferriss Show&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;99percentinvisible.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;99% Invisible&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.npr.org&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;510307&#x2F;invisibilia&quot;&gt;Invisibilia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wnycstudios.org&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;radiolab&quot;&gt;Radiolab&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.iheart.com&#x2F;podcast&#x2F;105-stuff-you-should-know-26940277&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Stuff You Should Know&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;freakonomics.com&#x2F;archive&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;slate.com&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;working&quot;&gt;Working&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;awesomeatyourjob.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;How to be Awesome at Your Job&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.acquired.fm&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Acquired&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCehkUnsoTlHlFJ8FEYCz4nA&quot;&gt;That Creative Life&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.bbc.co.uk&#x2F;programmes&#x2F;p002w557&#x2F;episodes&#x2F;downloads&quot;&gt;Discovery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ted.com&#x2F;talks&quot;&gt;TED Talks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.npr.org&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;510298&#x2F;ted-radio-hour&quot;&gt;TED Radio Hour&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gimletmedia.com&#x2F;shows&#x2F;surprisingly-awesome&quot;&gt;Surprisingly Awesome&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.flashforwardpod.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Flash Forward&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;serialpodcast.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Serial&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.npr.org&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;500005&#x2F;story-of-the-day&quot;&gt;Story of the Day : NPR&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.intelligencesquared.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Intelligence Squared&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.storycollider.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Story Collider&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-list-for-2021&quot;&gt;My list for 2021&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every Day Grammer TV - Voice of America&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Monday Morning Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Smartest Man In The World&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait Wait... Don&#x27;t Tell Me!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myths and Legends&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phlilosophy Bites&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A History of The World in 100 Objects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Story Collider&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Moth&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence Squared&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story of the Day : NPR&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serial&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash Forward&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This American Life&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rationally Speaking&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brain Matters&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science Friday&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reply All&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TED Radio Hour&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surprisingly Awesome&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stuff You Should Know&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freakonomics Radio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to be Awesome at Your Job&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquired&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Creative Life&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovery&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99% Invisible&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invisibilia&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radiolab&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money For the Rest of Us&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Death, Sex and Money&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You Are Not So Smart&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TED Talks Daily Audio Selection&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geekstra&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gayrisafi Fikirler&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SBS World News Radio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apka Alt Konumalar&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mcadele&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arka Fon Hikayeleri&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luke&#x27;s English Podcast - Learn British with Luke&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ten Questions ESL Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just Vocabulary | ESL Podcast for Learning SAT and GRE Vocabulary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happy English Podcsat&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;podcastinenglish&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Espresso English Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go Nautral English Podcast | Listening &amp;amp; Speaking Lessons&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn English Through Listening&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culips English Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better at English - Free English conversation lessons podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Satr Aras&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parat&#x27;le retim Band&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Radyo 521&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gerisi Hikaye Korku Konumalar&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hayatlar Hikayeler&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Splendid Speaking&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comedy of The Week&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Book Club&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great Lives&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning English News Rewiews&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 Minute Grammer&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday Night Comedy from BBC Radio 4&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sesli Kitap&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embedded System Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastering Embedded Systems&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advantech Embedded - IOT Europa&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software Engineering Radio - The Podcast for Professionals&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gnn ve Gncelin Edebiyat&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kodpod&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Our Time : Philosophy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Codefiction Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Words and Their Stories - Voice of America&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haluk Tatar - Yol Sohbetleri&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ngilizce Sohbeti&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bar zcan&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Akimboo: A Podcast from Seth Godin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weekly Dev Tips&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WSJ&#x27;s The Future of Everything&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disik Didik Freud&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sosyal Psikolojiden Sevgilerle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hidden Brain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor&#x27;s picks from the Economist&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haftalk Gndem Deerlendirmesi&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metro FM - Aragaz&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planet Money&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ak Bilim Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Ears English Podcast&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The English We Speak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bunu Ben De Yaparm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 Minute Vocabulary&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lk Sayfas&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fularsz Entellik&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 Minute English&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psikolog Beyhan Budak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ngilizce Saati&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virgin Radio - Mesut Sre ile Rabarba&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Mask</title>
        <published>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-mask/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-mask/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-please-hear-what-i-m-not-saying&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Please Hear What I&#x27;m Not Saying&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t be fooled by me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t be fooled by the face I wear&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for I wear a mask, a thousand masks,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;masks that I&#x27;m afraid to take off,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and none of them is me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretending is an art that&#x27;s second nature with me,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but don&#x27;t be fooled,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for God&#x27;s sake don&#x27;t be fooled.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give you the impression that I&#x27;m secure,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that all is sunny and unruffled with me, within as well as without,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that confidence is my name and coolness my game,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that the water&#x27;s calm and I&#x27;m in command&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that I need no one,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but don&#x27;t believe me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My surface may seem smooth but my surface is my mask,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ever-varying and ever-concealing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beneath lies no complacence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beneath lies confusion, and fear, and aloneness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I hide this. I don&#x27;t want anybody to know it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I panic at the thought of my weakness exposed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s why I frantically create a mask to hide behind,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a nonchalant sophisticated facade,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to help me pretend,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to shield me from the glance that knows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But such a glance is precisely my salvation, my only hope,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I know it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, if it&#x27;s followed by acceptance,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if it&#x27;s followed by love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s the only thing that can liberate me from myself,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from my own self-built prison walls,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from the barriers I so painstakingly erect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s the only thing that will assure me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of what I can&#x27;t assure myself,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that I&#x27;m really worth something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I don&#x27;t tell you this. I don&#x27;t dare to, I&#x27;m afraid to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m afraid your glance will not be followed by acceptance,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will not be followed by love.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m afraid you&#x27;ll think less of me,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that you&#x27;ll laugh, and your laugh would kill me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m afraid that deep-down I&#x27;m nothing&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and that you will see this and reject me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I play my game, my desperate pretending game,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with a facade of assurance without&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and a trembling child within.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So begins the glittering but empty parade of masks,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and my life becomes a front.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I idly chatter to you in the suave tones of surface talk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell you everything that&#x27;s really nothing,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and nothing of what&#x27;s everything,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of what&#x27;s crying within me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I&#x27;m going through my routine&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;do not be fooled by what I&#x27;m saying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please listen carefully and try to hear what I&#x27;m not saying,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what I&#x27;d like to be able to say,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what for survival I need to say,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but what I can&#x27;t say.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t like hiding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t like playing superficial phony games.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to stop playing them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be genuine and spontaneous and me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but you&#x27;ve got to help me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#x27;ve got to hold out your hand&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;even when that&#x27;s the last thing I seem to want.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only you can wipe away from my eyes&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the blank stare of the breathing dead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only you can call me into aliveness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each time you&#x27;re kind, and gentle, and encouraging,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;each time you try to understand because you really care,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my heart begins to grow wings--&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;very small wings,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;very feeble wings,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but wings!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your power to touch me into feeling&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can breathe life into me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to know that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to know how important you are to me,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;how you can be a creator--an honest-to-God creator--&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of the person that is me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you choose to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You alone can break down the wall behind which I tremble,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you alone can remove my mask,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you alone can release me from my shadow-world of panic,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from my lonely prison,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if you choose to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please choose to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not pass me by.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will not be easy for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long conviction of worthlessness builds strong walls.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nearer you approach to me the blinder I may strike back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s irrational, but despite what the books say about man&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;often I am irrational.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fight against the very thing I cry out for.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am told that love is stronger than strong walls&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and in this lies my hope.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please try to beat down those walls&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with firm hands but with gentle hands&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for a child is very sensitive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I, you may wonder?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am someone you know very well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I am every man you meet&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and I am every woman you meet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles C. Finn&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;September 1966&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tr-maske&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Tr&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Maske&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bana aldrmayn!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yzm bir maskedir,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sizi aldatmasn,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binlerce maskem var,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;karmaya korktuum&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ve&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hibiri ben deilim.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beni kendi maskelerimden kurtaracak&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kurduum hapishaneden karacak&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diktiim engellerden aracak&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beni seven,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beni anlayan&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baklar olacak;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bana,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Sen deerlisin&amp;quot; diyecek,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Maskesizken, daha bir insansn&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Daha yakn, daha bir dostsun&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diyecek bir baka,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beni gren bir baka&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muhtacm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benim yanma sokulmak kolay olmayacaktr!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uyarrm seni dost!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uzun yllar kendimi yetersiz hissetmi ben,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sana kendimi kolayca amayacaktr.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Btn gcmle tutunacam maskelerime,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ne kadar sokulursan yanma,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O denli iddetli geri iteceim seni.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim olduumu merak ediyor musun?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi merak etme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben evrendeki&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her erkek ve kadnm,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maske takan her insanm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles C. Finn&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>My faded flowers</title>
        <published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/my-faded-flowers/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/my-faded-flowers/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-my-faded-flowers&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) My faded flowers&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mom had given her best flowers to me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took, I looked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were faded,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#x27;t look..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tr-ciceklerim&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Tr&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) ieklerim&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annem en gzel ieklerini bana vermiti.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aldm, baktm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kurudular,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bakamadm..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Ben gone</title>
        <published>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-ben-gone/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-ben-gone/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-ben-gone&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The Ben gone&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing made me was me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You took it from me,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remaing, is me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is disparate, not me..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tr-giden-ben&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Tr&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Giden Ben&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beni ben yapan bendim.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O beni benden aldnz,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kalan, benim.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bu ben bambaka, ben deil..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
