<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>RustyNotes - Study Notes</title>
    <subtitle>A journey with some Rust</subtitle>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com/categories/study-notes/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://rustynotes.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://rustynotes.com/categories/study-notes/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 3</title>
        <published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-3/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-3/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-phrases&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about phrases&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;phrases&quot;&gt;Phrases&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Braek down: to stop functioning
Call off: to cancel
Come accross: to find unexpectedly
Look after: to take care of
Bring up: to mention or introduce a topic
Go on: to contunie
Turn up: to arrive
Give up: to stop trying
Bring back: to return
Hold on: to wait
Take off: to remove clothing or to depart(airplane)
Set up: to establish or arrange
Get along: to have a good relationship
Look for: to search for
Put off: to postpone
Turn down: to reject or decrease
Give in: to surrender
Get over: to recover from
Look up: to search for information
Turn on: to switch on
Put up with: to tolerate
Break in: to enter unlawfully
Come up with: to propose or think of
Go through: to experience or endure
Catch up: to reach the same level
Take after: to resemble proudly
Show off: to display proudly
Pass away: to die
Point out: to indicate or mention
Bring about: to cause
Hold back: to restrain or withhold
Break out: to start suddenly
Carry on: to continue
Turn off: to switch off
Point out: to indicate or mention
Bring about: to cause
Check in: to register or arrive
Fill out: to complete a form
Run into: to encounter unexpectedly
Take up: to begin a hobby or activity
Turn into: to transform into
Back up: to support or reverse &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>About colors</title>
        <published>2022-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/about-colors/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/about-colors/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-about-colors&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) About colors&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was watching a video about colors from Youtube channel RobWords. Let&#x27;s list some details for colors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;black&quot;&gt;Black&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This color is very old and seems like originated from proto-indo-european language word bhleg and proto-germanic word blakaz. They mean burning and burned.In English it is related with Blank and this rooteda French word &#x27;blanc. But blanc means white.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like one picked the shining side of burning flames and the other picked the dark side of burned things. In the end, both of them are related with burning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;white&quot;&gt;White&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is orginiated from proto-indo-european word kweido. Wheat is alsofrom same root. The grained wheat is also white. The word similarity makes sense.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;blue&quot;&gt;Blue&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is the newest one. Ancient civilizations didn&#x27;t have a word for blue. Homer were discribing the sea as wine dark. Greeks were calling the sky with browm, shineness rather than hue. Old germanic languages were discrebing the color of sky with blaw and haewen. They mean bright and kind of gray. When you think about north-sea it makes sense. Italiens call the sky in the clear day Azuro not blue. Blue is darker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;brown&quot;&gt;Brown&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one comes from brun and it means bright. Burnish is also from same word, means to polish something. Making more bright and shiny. The second mean of brun was drity and the word brown has been fixed to this meaning in 13. century.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;green&quot;&gt;Green&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green is rooted from proto-indo-european word gwher. It means to grow and to become green. It is related with grass and grow. The word grass is also from same root.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;orange&quot;&gt;Orange&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fruit orange comes before color. The fruit was naranj in sanskrit, narang in persian. It was naranj in arabic, naranja in spanish. It was orange in french, orange in english. The fruit was named after the color.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;red&quot;&gt;Red&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one is rooted from proto-indo-european word reudh. It means red and ruddy. It is related with rust and ruby. The word rust is also from same root.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;yellow&quot;&gt;Yellow&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It comes from the word gelwaz in proto germanic language. It passed to old english as gelo. It seems like gold and refers the old proto-indo-european word for shine. It should be related with gold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Python journey</title>
        <published>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/python-journey/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/python-journey/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-python-journey&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Python Journey&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we should keep in mind and stick with it is committing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to use the language we want to improve every day for 6 month.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Looking back</title>
        <published>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/looking-back/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/looking-back/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-looking-back&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Looking back&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life was not something we imagine. It was a really hard pill to Swallow. We didn&#x27;t know but even no-brainers will reach to end in some way. The important thing is what do you see when you look back in that point. When you shift that point through present from the end you will have a insight about your path and actions in that path. Back propagation of observe will reach to today and hit you. You may wish to go back to square one and live the life in proper in a better way. That will be beating a dead horse, there is no way to have totally happy or perfect life. Without problem and lackness nothing will have value and mean. So keeping eyes peeled and repeating the obverstion from future to past will help us to understand what we are doing and where we are going. This activity will probably prevent regret in the future. Life might seem a thing you can just go for broke and this might be right however we can feel more free by going future and looking back to shape our current days and decisions. Hope for that the imagination will set us free, at least from the present.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;phrases&quot;&gt;PHRASES&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard Pill to Swallow&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: Something that&#x27;s difficult to accept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Ropes&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: Being in a situation that looks to be hopeless!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go For Broke&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: To risk it all, even if it means losing
everything. To go all out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep Your Eyes Peeled&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: To be watchful; paying careful attention to something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear, Hear&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: A shout of agreement, or to draw attention to a speaker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No-Brainer&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: Anything that requires minimal brain activity to accomplish.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing Possum&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: Pretending to be dead, or to be deceitful about something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to Square One&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: To go back to the beginning; back to the drawing board.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Par For the Course&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: What you would expect to happen; something normal or common.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beating a Dead Horse&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meaning: To bring up an issue that has already been resolved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Mistakes</title>
        <published>2022-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/mistakes/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/mistakes/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-mistakes&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The mistakes&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I have recognized that there is a saying on my green t-shirt while I was looking in to mirror. It says that &amp;quot;I will do better mistakes tomorrow&amp;quot;. I have been wearing this t-shirt for several years and I have just seen these words. I think it suggests a very important thing for our lives. Some mistakes can be resulted very badly and might be hard to endure for us in this world but most mistakes are part of our existance. As the old saying says &amp;quot;if you don&#x27;t do mistakes that means you don&#x27;t live and just exist&amp;quot;. We might have a quota for mistakes and we should have them in an acceptable amount but we must have mistakes, even lots of them. But the important thing is learning and getting lessons from them, this is supposed to be our weapon in chaos and a tool for adaptation. Some features will be remaining and after the election, we will be trying a new version of ourselves. Then this new version will be tested in several ways and the shaping process of life will be continuous by this loop. A soul dipped in sorrow and failures is better than a soul full of regret for not attempting mistakes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;WORDS&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feather&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;endure&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dip&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weapon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quota&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;suppose&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;election&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grass&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eclipse&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The resistance</title>
        <published>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-resistance/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-resistance&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The resistance&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no rule and order in context and title. They are just a piece of my daily feelings, experience, and learning progress.
Today I have just decided to write about resistance. Because yesterday I couldn&#x27;t start to write.
I wanted but there was no idea and motivation. Creating a habit is always hard because we are not able to see the future and end of our path.
We may feel satisfied but also we can regret it after spending some years. When we force ourselves to do what we don&#x27;t want we treat ourselves like a maid.
At this point there should be a border, we shouldn&#x27;t tyrannize ourselves and should find a way and create a tactic to keep us on our way but also
train us by having tough times. We need to evoke ourselves in a way and see what we are doing. Otherwise, it might be too late for decisions and change.
There is no exact truth but searching and having a meaning and goal will be helpful for the future.
To develop our credibility we should look to people who have a better life and read about their lives so we can decide more wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exact&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;satisfied&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;credibility&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;channel&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cassette&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;habit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tactic&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evoke&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The goal and way of writing</title>
        <published>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-goal-and-way-of-writing/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-the-goal-and-way-of-writing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) The Goal and way of writing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method is very old. We all get lessons about it but we don&#x27;t pay enough attention because writing is a boring activity for children. So we grow up without improving this skill enough. After some years of experience in business and also communication paths in daily life we understand how important is the usage of language and richness in vocabulary. Now we all know that communication skills and consistency are the most important skills in life. So, we need to improve ourselves in these skills. According to Jordan Peterson, we need to write more and more to use the language more effectively and order our ideas to think more clearly and properly. By that time I have been thinking about consistency and effective ways of getting this skill. By getting an impression from the homework the teacher gave us and suggesting to do more, I decided to write consistently, almost every day. These two activities will be a perfect fit for lots of problems especially are related to personal identification, communication, and expression. The way of doing this is by defining 10 random words and using 6 of them in a context. Cooperation by others will make it more interesting, interactive, and also more effective. Because seeing others&#x27; writings about the same words will improve our creativity and our own writing. The rhythm we have and keep for that habit will define our progress. When we execute this plan well we will get lifelong durable and very important skills. Otherwise, we will be in the case of resigning ourselves to the lives we don&#x27;t like because of weak character and personality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identification&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resign&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cooperation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amputate&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diamond&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rhythm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fit&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;execute&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rugby&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 2</title>
        <published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-2/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-describing&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about describing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;words&quot;&gt;Words&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catchy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : memorable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;commercial&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : converned with or engaged in commerce&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;disturbing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : causing anxiety; worrying&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dull&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : lacking interest or exciment&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gripping&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : firmly holding the attention or interest; exciting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hilarious&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : extremely amuzing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;over-the-top&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : to an excessive or exaggerated degree&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;uplifting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : inspiring happiness, optimism or hope&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;weird&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; : uncanny&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sentences&quot;&gt;Sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It didn&#x27;t do much for me. It&#x27;s very commercial.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is just too much for my liking, really over-the-top.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does nothing for me. It&#x27;s quite boring, quite dull.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: What kind of thing do you do in your free time?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;B: I guess the films are the main thing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A: Really. Do you go cinema much then?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah. I mean it depend&#x27;s what&#x27;s on.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;m happy just to watch at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t you want to see it on the big screen?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be honest, I am not that keen on action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suppose, I&#x27;d rather see other things.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was so over-the-top. That scene where he eats the live octopus! It was all a bit too weird for my liking.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C: As I said, it is not really my kind of thing. So what other films are you into?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;D: Oh all sorts. (every type!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;m really into action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;ve heard it is good. I was actually thinking of going to see it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought it was supposed to be a feel-good movie.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did they think of them?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;disaggrements&quot;&gt;Disaggrements&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess but &lt;strong&gt;to be honest I&#x27;m not that keen on&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; action movies.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was all &lt;strong&gt;a bit too&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; weird &lt;strong&gt;for my liking.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I say, it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;not really my kind of thing.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was not bad, &lt;strong&gt;I suppose but ..&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often soften responses by using phrases such as &lt;strong&gt;I&#x27;m not that keen on, I guess, I suppose, to be honest, for my liking..&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We also use &lt;strong&gt;a bit&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to soften negative adjectives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;quotes-about-art&quot;&gt;Quotes about art&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art is the lie that enables us to realise the truth.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art is what you can get away with.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urge of destroy is also a creative urge.(&lt;em&gt;urge: impulse, desire&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The more minimal the art, the longer the explanation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Art never responds to the wish to make it democratic; it is not for everybody; it is only for those who are willing to undergo the effort needed to understand it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;descriptive-sentences&quot;&gt;Descriptive sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold colours are very bright, strong and clear, whereas subtle colours are not strong or bright. They&#x27;re softer and more delicate.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  delicate: (fine, elegant) very fine in texture or structure, of intricate workmanship or quality. Ex: A spider&amp;#39;s web is stong yet delicate
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  subtle: (fine-drawn, ultra-fine, elusive) so delicate or precise as to be difficult to analyze or describe. Ex: His language expresses rich and subtle meanings.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a painting is &lt;strong&gt;conventional&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, it&#x27;s traditional and not new or different in any way.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  conventional: based on or in accordance with what is generally done or believed.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;atmospheric&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, a painting creates a special mood - such as a feeling of romance or mystery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&#x27;s &lt;strong&gt;ambiguous&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, the meaning of the work isn&#x27;t clear - it&#x27;s oepn to interpretation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;intimate&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; painting shows private moments in someone&#x27;s life.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  intimate: closely acquinted, familiar, close. (as noun: a very close friend)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main character has his back to the viewer, which creates a feeling of mystery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;looks as if&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; he&#x27;s thinking about killing himself.(as if + sentence)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He is &lt;strong&gt;obviously&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a sad and lonely man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the most important thing in the painting. Ex: The car &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be running well. Everyone &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; have thought the same thing. He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; know the facts. This house &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be empty. He &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be losing. She &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be sad. That &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the hardest word I&#x27;ve learned. It &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be working, though I don&#x27;t know for sure. It &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be good. What &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be the problem here? She &lt;strong&gt;seems to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be losing her mind.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;appears to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be looking for something better than what he was.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He looks very proud. I get the impression he feels very pleased with himself.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He &lt;strong&gt;looks like&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; a very wealthy man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be someone in Europe. It &lt;strong&gt;could well&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be France.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who do you think people in there might be?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you think they&#x27;re feeling?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What might the connection between the two works be?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what way are two paintings connected?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what way might the viewer&#x27;s first impression of the paintings be wrong?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sentences-1&quot;&gt;Sentences&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow me &lt;strong&gt;through into&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the next room.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He died &lt;strong&gt;at the age of 37&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;at a time&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; when his career was going well and since then he has been forgotten, which &lt;strong&gt;seems to a bit of a shame&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, to be honest.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These two paintings were meant to be hung together as &lt;strong&gt;companion&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; pieces.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  companion: a person or animal with whom one spends a lot time with whom one travels
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He was &lt;strong&gt;composing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the letter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  compose: write or create (a work of art, especially music or poetry).Prepare (a text) for printing by manually, mechancally or electronically setting up the letters and other characters in order to be printed.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;She is &lt;strong&gt;digesting&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; it.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  digest: break down (food) in the alimentary canal into substances that can be absorbed and used by the body.(sindirmek)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His surroundings create the impression that he&#x27;s well travelled.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He&#x27;s man of the world.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woman seems to belong more to the domestic world. She looks calm and &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; as she reads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  content: a state of peaceful happiness
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, not everything is as it first appears. &lt;strong&gt;Beneath&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the surface of the calm domestic world lies trouble.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  beneath: at a lower level or layer than
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously, the woman was so excited to receive her letter that she jumped up in the middle of her needleworkk.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;could well&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be a symbol of the difficult, stormy nature of love, especially when partners are seperated. There is another letter to deliver, &lt;strong&gt;presumably&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to the man.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even he, &lt;strong&gt;depicted&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in darker, more subtle shades, is a victim of the fires of the heart. The rich red of carpet and the bright &lt;strong&gt;light pouring&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in through the window suggest he has a &lt;strong&gt;heated mind&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.(angry and excited)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  depict: show or represent by a drawing, painting, or other art form
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The underlying message now seems &lt;strong&gt;painfully clear&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: passion can lead to chaos.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;  painfully clear: it is embrassing because it is so clear&#x2F;obvious&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>English notes 1</title>
        <published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-1/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/english-notes-1/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-english-study-about-entertainment&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) English study about entertainment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where do you think the place is?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you want to read in a place like this?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you usually take a book with you when you&#x27;re travelling or do you prefer e-book readers?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&#x27;s the nicest or most unusual place that you&#x27;ve spent time reading in?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you read much?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-answers&quot;&gt;Example answers:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like all kinds of stuff as well -rock, pop, even some classical.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t tend to during the week, though, because I&#x27;ve got to get up early and basically my parents prefer me to stay at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as much as I&#x27;d like to, because I really love it - especially musicals. The seats are so expensive I can&#x27;t afford to go more than a couple  of times a year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find it a bit boring. It&#x27;s not really my kind of thing and I&#x27;m not very good at it either.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably less than I think I do. It&#x27;s always on in the background, you know, but I don&#x27;t pay much attention to it most of the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will watch a big game if there2s one on and the occasional film, but apart from that, most of it&#x27;s rubbish.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah, I guess so. I generally cycle to college as well -unless it&#x27;s raining.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend to watch films on demand through my TV at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not as much as I used to.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vocab&quot;&gt;Vocab:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now and again   -   ?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tend to     -&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;habit-s-grammer&quot;&gt;Habit&#x27;s Grammer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;past&quot;&gt;Past:&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk about past habits, we can use the past simple, used to + infinitive(without to) or would + infinitive(without to). Examples:&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listened to music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used to listen music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;d listen to music all the time when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;present&quot;&gt;Present:&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To talk about current habits we can use the present simple, tend to + infinitive(without to) and will + infinitive(without to)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listen to music all the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend to watch films on demand through my TV.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;adverbs-and-adverbal-phrases-for-frequency&quot;&gt;Adverbs and adverbal phrases for frequency:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;always, all the time, constantly&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;normally, usually, as a rule, one the whole, by and large&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes, now and again, once in a while&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;almost never, very rarely, hardly ever, once in a blue moon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not as much as  + I&#x27;d like to &#x2F; I want &#x2F; I used to &#x2F; I did before&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-negatives-for-habits&quot;&gt;Making negatives for habits&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can make negatives with tend to and used to in different ways.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&#x27;t use to like it very much.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I never used to listen to music at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend not to go to the cinema that much.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mistakes&quot;&gt;Mistakes:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t say &lt;em&gt;use to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about habits in the present. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;use to&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;usually&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;tend to&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; go out with friends on a Friday.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use the past continuous to talk about past habits. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;was going&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;went&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;used to go&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; swimming a lot when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use &lt;em&gt;would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about character and other kinds of states. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I (&lt;del&gt;would have&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;had&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; &#x2F; &lt;strong&gt;used to have&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; long hair when I was younger.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t use &lt;em&gt;how&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; instead of as in comparatives. Ex:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t go as much (&lt;del&gt;how&lt;&#x2F;del&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;as&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; I&#x27;d like to.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;did-you-know&quot;&gt;Did you know?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is actually far more common than &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to talk about past habits. That&#x27;s because while we often introduce a topic with &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we tend to give details with &lt;em&gt;would&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Ex:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;used to make&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; my own films when I was younger. &lt;strong&gt;I&#x27;d watch&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; famous films and get ideas and then my brother and I &lt;strong&gt;would try&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to make our own versions. &lt;strong&gt;We&#x27;d then do&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; screenings for our family.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;Ex:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By and large, I don&#x27;t tend to watch TV much. There are too many ads, which annoys me.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#x27;t see her as much as I used to, because we&#x27;re both so busy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Golden halfmoon</title>
        <published>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/golden-halfmoon/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-town&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Town&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town we will talk about is Halfeti. It is part of the city named Sanliurfa which is famous for being the source of religion in the world. In my country, we call this city the city of prophets. Because lots of prophets have been there during history, like Muse, Abraham, Elyasa, Adem, Ayub. And also a temple named Göbeklitepe dates back to 9500 BC.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During endless stream of time, the city managed to survive in mandatory of different countries. In this matter, the town Halfeti has a unique position in one respect. It has a castle in the middle of the river which were defining the border of the Eastern Roman Empire. When you see the picture of the castle you see how fairly reasonable to build it there. It is like the wall in the game of thrones. Because the river still defines the east in Turkey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pass the west side you should pass across the river. Besides, according to the book Homo Sapiens, the River Euphrates defines the Fertile Crescent with another river named Tigris. The region around these two rivers was very productive and important during history so the agriculture, religion, and writing were sourced from Fertile Crescent. Nowadays, the situation is slightly different. Rivers are still very important but industries were not established there. Despite being so historic they don&#x27;t have enough amenities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Halfeti people has a living just from agriculture. The discovery of the first temple of the world in Urfa started to attract tourists. Moreover, having a sub-merged town under the river makes the Halfeti attractive for tourists. Some parts are photogenic but it was a ghost town when I was a child. Nowadays, it is a lively town with sailing, canoe, and diving amenities. There are not many residents and no imposing buildings. Also, because of the narrow streets, I suggest that to leave your car on the main road and walk. Because it is a Cita Slow with a gentle rhythm and a self-contained environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The middle man</title>
        <published>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/the-middle-man/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-middle-men-and-old-man&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) Middle men and old man&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle. Middle of what? Who knows? He always felt like this without any idea for reason. He was brought up in a conservative family that potentially was in the heart of his life. But he doesn&#x27;t want to remember those days anymore. He knows how he felt after expelling from school and being like on the ledge of family. His father was like a sheer wall for every discussion and preventing him to shape his own way. Maybe that was because of buzzing news about war and the bad economy, but there should have been more. He has never known that. Because, after staying in the zone and hard working he got the foot in the door of university and left them behind. He hasn&#x27;t looked back after this moment and flashed around the country with his exam scores. Everyone was stunned because it was impossible to work flawlessly in that conditions. It was merely a small possibility to rally after this long period of indolence life. But they had forgotten how greasy he is for his decisions and after deciding to his way how hard to change his mind. Now he was at the summit of Mont Blanc and has just signed the summit book. He was standing on his planted steps with an old feeling like being in the middle of a low surrounding.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a man with a pencil in the middle of foreigners. They had come from far but he was from the city. Unlike others, he felt fatigued in the middle of the way but he rallied by staying in the zone and pushing towards his limits. In the end, these bad feelings turned into being stunned due to the accomplishment of this goal. Because it was a merely impossible dream for someone at that age. After he explained his decision, all family members warned him about how this event potentially can kill him. They said that he was in the heart of the family and he shouldn&#x27;t do that. However, it was not true and he has felt like he is on the ledge of the family until this moment. Now he was standing over planted steps in the summit. This was the point he got his foot in the door of climbing and became the oldest person who climbed to Mont Blanc. The news was buzzing this journey and it flashed around the world.
(&lt;em&gt;by listening blues&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man was fainted due to lack of sleep and fatigue. Because he had already been sick. Writing and staying in the zone for several hours was potentially dangerous. The doctor and all family members warned him but after getting his foot in the door of writing he became more undeterred and it was impossible to dissuade him. He was a famous writer and had flashed around the world once upon a time. So, even getting stuck in some points he rallied to finish this book before the party. The book was supposed to be a birthday gift the next day. There was merely a small time before the party and the book was finally completed. Everything was working flawlessly according to his plan. The girl would be stunned when she saw the book had written for her. The old man closed the book and named it by using one of the greasy tags. He wasn&#x27;t aware of the broken door ledge and also that the name will have been buzzing in the news the next day. Because it was the last book of a great writer who was at the summit of his career. During his long and successful journey, he hasn&#x27;t looked back but it was time to rest last time. By this book, an old saying is brought up again. There is no reward without taking risks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;by listening rock&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Tennis work notes</title>
        <published>2018-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/tennis-work-notes/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://rustynotes.com/all-posts/tennis-work-notes/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eng-tr-my-tennis-notes&quot;&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Eng-Tr&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) My Tennis Notes&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ağırlığı arka ayağa ver, vuruşlarda&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serviste hız değil verimi arttır. İkide iki olmalı.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oynarken harekete odaklan ve stabilleştir.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sürekli yeni şeyler deneme, ilerlemeye * çalış mevcut düzende.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Servislerde derin nefes al&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;exercies-for-tennis&quot;&gt;Exercies for tennis&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;legs&quot;&gt;LEGS&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wall-sits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lateral band walk&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glute bridges&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squats&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;strong-core&quot;&gt;STRONG CORE&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planks&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medicine balls&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steaked V-sits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standing abs&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lean-upper-body&quot;&gt;LEAN UPPER-BODY&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push-ups&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chin-up&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicep curls&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kettlebells&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;footwork-drills&quot;&gt;FOOTWORK DRILLS&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladder agility drills&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On-count drills&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
